[music]
Hey, hey, hey. [music]
>> [music]
[music]
>> Heat. Heat. [music]
>> [music]
[music]
>> Hello, good evening and good day
everybody. Welcome back to the Ask Kabit
show. This is episode 323.
I hope you're all doing great. I'm going
to take questions from the super chat
and the live chat today. Ask me
anything. I'll answer as much as I can.
Before we get into the questions, let us
see who all is there on the live chat. I
can see Mac J1U. Mac 4 J1U. Basker
Bandit, Mary Kane, good evening, Mary,
good to see you. Good, good morning.
Good morning, Mary. Uh, died in a plane
crash. KS111
uh died in a plane crash all over again.
Geopolitical Dubai is here from Indor.
Good evening, Sentinel Spy. Yo, Neil
7070707,
Jawa Stellar. Uh, Real Painter,
Adwit, Ashwini, Aush Gupta, uh, Kaneska
K4, Nishk K. Um, who else do we have?
Shivasai, Amy Tulp from Germany. Well,
good evening from Germany to to Germany.
Mna Kotari, good evening. Real painter
once again. Shiva Sai Adat Ashwini
Gajjapati Dva from Odisha good evening.
Good evening indeed. Swami 0709.
Um Shila Jabi Namaskarum namaskarum
indeed. Nagarand Shanai is here from
Hyderabad namaste to you. Nabaradas
namaste namaste to you as well.
Heisenberg O2J hello NJ.
Pratik Va hello Aayush Singh Pranam.
Pranam Himmanu Rajhit is here from
Chennai. Well good to have you Himmanu
G. Swami is here from Jaipur. Real
painter once again died in a plane
crash. Ritik Pawar. Aayush Singh uh
Raguir Soleni Vishba student. Vishba
student. Vikash PJ good evening. Uh
Shatabish is here from Norway. Well good
afternoon I suppose in Norway.
Demani um Ram Shreasaval
Kot Avin Tatagat Karan Shivasai Shrui
Patak Namaskar Maklein good evening good
evening Abhishek Shukla live Vikash PJ
Heisenberg everybody else general
subatai is here well good to see you
general sir random skull good evening
good to have you once again Anandvi
Rajes nine animals for laugh from Mumbai
Good evening. Good evening. Lava,
namaste. Namaste. Good to see you,
ma'am. Aniket Bomik Min once again.
Manish. Namaste. Namaste indeed. Um, who
else? Goami is also here. Hello. General
once again. Vin Bagalot. Heny Penguin.
Hello. Good to see you. Hi Penguin.
Anand from Karnataka. Carwar.
Okay. Lava is here from the USA. Well,
good morning USA and Lava G. Rahul Dun.
Namaskar. Namaskar and everyone else as
well.
Um, UKC from Australia.
Straa. Straa. Okay. So, um, Progressive
Pujan is here from the chicken neck.
Well, hope things are good at the
chicken neck. Okay. Let's get going with
the questions. What questions do we
have? Uh, the first question is by Mac 4
J1U. Few episodes ago you said only
Krishna himself could save our religion
after the UGC rules. I know why you said
it. Can you Okay. Yeah. The UGC rules,
right? Terrible. Absolutely terrible.
I'm not sure what the government is
trying to achieve. Um yeah, terrible
indeed. Uh can you describe how Ba Ral
resisted the Turks and Arabs and why
after him no one came?
So Baba Rahul is a warrior, a king from
the 8th century AD.
I'm not sure if we know exactly when he
lived and
what period of time he ruled, but it's
most likely that he ruled in the 8th
century AD. He was he belonged to the
to the Guhilot
uh clan of the Rajputs. At the time they
were not called Rajputs. The the term
Rajput was used later to describe uh the
old ruling uh families of India. And he
was part of one of these old ruling
families, the the Rahul lineage, Maywar
lineage I believe. And uh he
reconquered many parts of northern and
western India from the Arab occupiers of
the region. He conquered Gori Gazn Gazni
etc. right which is Gandhar present day
Afghanistan. And uh
and he obviously established the city
that's now called Rahul Pindi right. So
he was a great warrior. He defeated the
Arabs. I'm not sure if the Turks were
involved in India at the time. It was
mainly the Arabs. It was in the seventh
or 8th century that you have Muhammad
bin Kasim who makes an incursion into
Sind and does pretty nasty stuff there.
So that's the beginning of the Arabic
invasions which lasted a while and then
you have you know the phase of the Turk
invasions that comes later. So I believe
Bakar Raal would have fought the Arabs,
not the Turks and uh he did a pretty
good job of that. He reconquered many
territories that had been captured by
the Arabs and uh yeah so that's why he
is still remembered today and it's this
happened so long ago and we've lost all
the records. That's why he is regarded
that's why there is some ambiguity some
some this this we there there's a lack
of clarity as to exactly what were the
years during which he ruled these parts
of uh northern and western India so
that's the deal I about papa Raul why
did no one after him come it's not like
no one came after him you know in
northern and western India the people
that are now called the Rajuts they
resisted first the Arabic uh incursions
uh invasions of India and then the Turk
invasions of India for several
centuries. Uh
when is the Delhi Sultenate established?
Okay, let's let's take a look at the
dates. Okay, so 8th century you have
Babar who's fighting off the Arabs.
Okay, when was the Delhi Sultenate
established? Let's take a look. Delhi
Sultanate.
Uh so that is 1206.
So from the 8th century to 1206 that's
about 500 years. 500 years you had India
fighting off the the the Arabs and then
the Turks. Five centuries we're talking
about. And even with the Delhi Sultenate
it doesn't become very large right it
doesn't become very large and then you
have the Muggal Kingdom which becomes
the Muggal Empire. That also takes time.
So India fought, India resisted but we
not taught this. And that's why we we
get the impression that after papar
nobody came and nobody fought and every
the talks just won. That's not the case.
There was tremendous resistance for
centuries
right it was the people who are now
called the Rajputs who fought who
resisted for centuries.
They shed oceans of blood which we are
not told about and so on. So yeah it's
because our history textbooks like to
omit these parts of history. the Indian
resistance to the Arabic and uh Turk
invasions. Okay.
Basar Bandit says, "Piety Pyth
uh hope you're doing great. I'm I'm
doing great. I hope you're doing great
as well. Why are US veterans treated
badly in the US? PTSD, drug use, no
support system, homelessness in Bharat,
we see and treat army with respect to re
reverance and highest dignity.
Um
why is it so? Why why why do we in India
afford I mean give so much respect to
people who have served in the armed
forces veterans of the armed forces. Why
do Indians respect them so much?
It's because we are a very old culture
and civilization. And I'll tell you why.
Because in Indian culture
warriors weren't oppressors.
Okay? Warriors were defenders of
civilization.
Warriors weren't oppressors. Warriors
never oppressed people.
If if even if you had a period of time
where India was fragmented, divided into
multiple kingdoms and you had two
kingdoms fighting each other,
even then when one kingdom would let's
say let's say two kingdoms in Rajasthan
are fighting each other hypothetically
and one invades the other. So when one
invades the other, you have the armed
forces of the one getting invading the
territory of the other. And yet they
would never touch civilians. They would
never touch women, children or innocent
men. They would only fight the other
kingdom's armed forces,
right? That was a discipline that we
had, our our ancestors had. that that
was the civilized way of fighting which
obviously was terrible when we we came
up against the you know barbarians
essentially. Uh so because India's
warriors have always been civilized
warriors. They've never oppressed
civilians. They've never oppressed the
the weak, the the the innocent, the
harmless. That's why that thing that
that respect for warriors is there in in
in the blood of Indians in the DNA of
Indians. We simply respect warriors
because we know they're doing the right
thing. When it comes to the Anglo-Saxon
world, the European world, I mean, just
take the look at take a look at the
history of who warriors were and what
they did and who they served. They
served the feudal overlords. They served
the crown and who they did the
oppressed, their own people,
the peasantry of the their of the of the
same country of the same kingdom.
Right? So in the Anglo-Saxon world of
and in the European world warriors were
typically oppressors of the people of
their own kingdom kingdom and they were
pretty brutal. Their treatment of men,
women, children was pretty brutal and
that's consistent over time over
centuries.
Right? So that's the culture that you
have in the Anglo-Saxon world in the
European world. And when you know you
have someone who served in the US armed
forces is a veteran of some tour of duty
somewhere what kind of tour of duty did
would they typically have done? They
would have either been part of the
occupation of Iraq, Iraq, the occupation
of Afghanistan or some other nasty
business somewhere else. What do they do
there? They shoot civilians. They
plunder the place. They destroy the
place. the flattened cities. Do you
think that's something that's worthy of
respect?
Yeah. So, that's one reason why warriors
aren't really respected in the West,
right?
And u Yeah. So, and in the US, it's not
like, you know, the armed forces are a
career that you have for the rest of
your life. You may serve one tour of
duty and get out, you know, honorable
discharge or whatever kind of discharge
and then you're back in the civilian
world and then what do you do? If you
have some skills, then you can start
with another career. Some people don't
have skills and they end up on the
streets and then it's P PTSD, drug use,
etc., etc. And there's no support system
for them. So, it's a very different
culture. It's at a very different uh
cultural millu that we're talking about
the western world. It's not like India,
right? So, big difference. Big
difference here.
Mary Kane, good to see you, Mary. Good
to see you. Hope you're doing well.
Mary asks, "Why are India's logistics
capabilities?" Um, Army Corps of
Engineers in cooperation with the UP
government for Kumba level
infrastructure and security at Magabella
2026 15 cr so underplayed why not brag?
It's a great question. So when it comes
to the kumba, I think it was the the
kumba happened last year was it? Did it
possibly? When did the kumba happen?
Let's let's quickly take I think it was
last year [snorts] I am wondering
because I did not attend unfortunately u
last kumba
which year
it was 2013 the next 2020 2025
2025 priyag mahakuma
so I this is in Hindi okay So
okay so that's the deal. Uh there was a
kumillaa in Priyag
last year and if I recall correctly
about over 600 million people
participated in this the largest human
gathering in human history 660 million
people
something like that at least 600 million
people that's like almost half of
India's population that's larger than
the populations of most countries I
think it's larger than the population of
Europe What's Europe's population? Let's
take a look. Um, Europe population,
what's the population?
Okay, so it's slightly less than the
population of Europe. Europe's current
population is about 744 745 million
people and uh the Kamela saw over 600
million people uh attending
participating in Priyagra in just one
city at the sangam of the of the rivers
right incredible. So you need incredible
logistics logistical capabilities to be
able to handle this incredible influx
inflow of people without any major
incident of any kind right uh and
obviously the army corps of engineers
was involved in cooperation with the UP
government uh for all the infrastructure
for all the security and all the
logistical arrangements and whatnot
and you have a mug hook me 2026 I'm not
very aware of that let's see what is
this
mug Magma Magma
2026. Why is it all caps? That's okay.
Magma 2026 begins in Priyagra. Sacred
Magma has commenced. It's already
commenced at the Sangam attracting
millions of devotees for holy dips and
spiritual rituals etc. Magillaa is back
in pray magma 2026. Okay. January 3 to
February 15, 2026. And how many people
marry says 15 cr. That's 150 million.
That's another massive number of people
150 million people right uh so yeah the
the lo so it's clear that India's
logistical capabilities are mindboggling
to be to be very to be very honest right
mindboggling logistical capabilities and
yet uh these capabilities are kind of
underplayed no one really speaks about
this the media doesn't crow and harp
about it the government of India doesn't
boast about it why not boast why not
brag is what Mary asks. Well, it's
certainly something that's uh you know
worthy of uh of being proud of. Maybe
India should brag more about this. I
would say the thing is you know
logistics capabilities are obviously
very important but they don't
it's not something that allows you to
rule the world. It's it's one component
of you know if you are a superpower for
example you need to be good at lots of
things including logistics but more than
logistics what you really need to be
good at is uh technology and uh
manufacturing
and India isn't right that great right
now in technology and manufacturing so
the the factors that make you a major
geopolitical power global power those
factors if you look at them India is
kind of a little bit weak right now so
that's what people like to boast about
you know I am that our country is the
best let's say in research and
development and and technology we have
the best technological systems in the
world we have the best manufacturing
base in the world that's what China
likes to say logistics it's not that
that cool it's not that you know it
doesn't make you a world leader maybe
that's why it's kind of underplayed but
definitely it's it's something that's
incredible and maybe like Mari says
Indians should perhaps brag a little bit
more about it Yeah, she's right.
Absolutely. All right.
Died in a plane crash says since 2022,
there are truckloads of videos made on
YouTube about Russia's so-called coloniz
colonization of Siberia that Russia is
guilty of the same crimes as against
natives as the US. What's my opinion as
someone who has studied history in great
detail?
To be very fair, Russia also has
colonized vast parts of Eurasia, right?
I mean the duchi the duchi of Muscovi
was the small area around Moscow and
that emerged in the aftermath of
Russia's liberation from the Mongol yoke
that's several centuries ago before that
Russia's territory was Ukraine which is
Ukraine the original capital of the rose
people was Kiev
so that's where Russia belongs Ukraine
and Moscow that region and today Russia
has this gigantic ginormous territory it
controls which is part of Russia today.
All the eastern Siberian and so on
territory, right? So obviously Russia
colonized this territory. It it
conquered and occupied these
territories.
So does that mean that Russia is guilty
of the same crimes against natives as
the United States? It doesn't mean that.
That is a false equivalence. Russia did
not ever genocide people on anything
like the scale at which the Americans
genocided their natives.
Right? And even today if you look at I
mean I'm sure there must have been
clashes, there must have been strife,
there must have been violence but and
there must have been massacres here and
there. That sort of stuff happens when
there is conquest.
But there was no genocide.
What the Americans did to their natives
is nothing short of genocide. Please
understand that the Russians did not do
that. Of course they they were more
powerful and they took they grabbed they
stole the territory let's say of various
indigenous people in Siberia Tuva
Yakutya Saka blah blah blah all that
right but there was no genocide yeah
sure they must have um you know
dispossessed the natives of the
territories and and prevented them from
you know uh expressing their or or or or
or
or deprived them of their right of
self-determination and so on so forth.
That sort of thing must have happened,
of course. But Russia did not conduct
genocide. Russia did not wipe out
hundreds of millions of wild bison.
Russia did not do any of those things.
So you can't draw an equivalence between
what the what the you know what the
European colonizers, occupiers of the
Americas did visav what the Russians did
in their far east. It's simply not
correct. False equivalence. Right. So,
I'm not sure. I've not seen any of these
videos. [snorts]
Yeah. But if they're trying to claim
that Russia has conducted genocide or or
that Russia what what it did is similar
to what the Americans did in the
Americas, that's completely incorrect.
Completely incorrect.
Aayush Gupta says, "Good evening. Good
evening to you as well. Don't you think
this tariff on EU and also EU realizing
that in every war now they suffer the
most because the of the US will make
them united internally they will price
toughs to secure their future.
Okay, good question. So now the question
Aush is asking is that now
does the EU or do the EU nations finally
do they realize that the Americans have
been taking advantage of them and now
the Americans are imposing tariffs that
Donald Trump's administration is
imposing tariffs on the Europeans 10%
tariffs on everybody uh until June or
something and then it increases to to
25% until Greenland is handed over to
the US entirely, completely, etc. Right?
Uh, and of course that's on top of
whatever other tariffs that the Trump
administration may or may not have
imposed on various nations in the EU.
So, does this finally and and Trump
wants Greenland? He wants to just grab a
gigantic piece of territory that belongs
to Denmark. I mean, he wants to
dispossess dispossess his own ally of
its territory. I mean, what sort of
behavior is is this? This is nothing
short of just naked imperialism,
plain bullying, right? So will this
finally make the EU nations realize
that everywhere whatever happens they
are made, you know, they are they are
being pushed over by the US, the US is
bullying them. And will this now make
the EU nations unite and they will now
hopefully come together and resist and
oppose the US? Is is this finally going
to make this happen? Is has Trump and
his actions finally, you know, broken
broken the camel's back? Does it
represent the straw that breaks the
camel's back? That's the question. Well,
no. Nothing's going to happen. You see,
right now, Kier Star Tmer, the the PM,
the prime minister of the UK is saying
that we are opposed to uh the US
claiming uh Greenland and trying to
steal it from Denmark. and Mu Macron of
France has said that we will not accept
any of this ter we don't accept this is
very bad very bad behavior and we shall
oppose this uh this sort of endeavor by
Mr. Trump and so on. All words or talk.
And they've sent some soldiers to
Greenland, like 20, 30 soldiers
cumulatively.
See, the deal is this. The US owns the
EU. The US has penetrated the EU so
incredibly deeply
that every single EU leader is in power
because of the US. Okay?
They have deep connections with the US.
their pockets, their bank accounts, all
of that. They won't survive the day the
US decides this leader is not, you know,
good for us.
And they draw their legitimacy, their
power, whatever money they have, etc.,
from their connections with the US. They
simply can't do anything that that that
genuinely opposes the US. So what's
going to happen is various EU leaders
are going to make statements strong
statements condemning you know Trump's
uh strong armed tactics and so on and
they will all initially say that you
know what Greenland is a sovereign
Danish territory blah blah blah but
eventually what's going to happen is
that Denmark is going to be paid a
certain sum of money by the Trump
administration and Greenland is going to
be handed to the U US that's what's
going to happen this is already written
let's say it's done It's a feta
complete, right? Um, so essentially
nothing's going to happen. The EU will
keep on cowing to the US.
The NATO nations will do the same.
Please understand the major power in
Western Europe. It's not France, it's
not Germany, it's not Italy, it's not
Spain, it's not whatever else. It is the
US. The US dictates whatever happens and
they all just go along with that. So
nothing's going to change.
Ritik Pawar says as the US is creating a
new world odorop isn't this a good
opportunity for India to try and rise by
using the new rules since the old rules
are not helping us grow faster. What
India needs to do to rise like you like
you say like all of us want India needs
to reform its its internal
affairs. We need to have deeprooted
reforms in all the sectors whether it is
the uh you know it's whether it's about
improving the ease of doing business
cutting the red tape uh whether it is um
you know economic reforms whether it is
farm sector reforms whether it's
educational reforms India needs deep
reforms all over the place and that's
not happening you can't simply use new
rules to to rise. How are you going to
rise? How do you rise? You become a
manufacturing power. How do you become a
manufacturing power? By becoming a
genuine world leader in research and
development in technology. How can you
become a world leader in research and
development and technology? By having a
world-class education system. There are
no shortcuts to these things. We have to
reform all these sectors and nothing is
being done. So simply by using new
rules, there new rules are going to suit
the US. They're not going to suit India.
The new rules of the new world order are
going to seek to vasalize India to
ensure India never does these reforms.
Yeah. So what India needs to do is to do
the hard things to reform internally. Do
you see any reforms?
There we are.
Pascar Bandit says declining world
population decreasing sperm quality
every 10 years. Do you think allegedly
it's a move from major corporations
given we have so much microplastics BPA
phalates hormone endocrine disruptors
etc in our everyday lives
whether it's a conspiracy whether it's a
move whether it's just u an you know
undesirable side effect of whatever but
it is what it is the you know all these
factors are converging together to cause
a major decline in the world population
like you say all these factors, right?
Um, you see microplastics in in in
bodily tissue everywhere. Microplastics
in organs, in brain, in in testicles, in
in hearts, lungs, and you know, just
regular human tissue. U microplastics in
water, microplastics in foods,
microplastics everywhere. I'm sure it's
going to have delterious effects
downstream.
um you you have u and maybe that's
causing one of the factors that's
causing declining uh decreasing uh sperm
quality every 10 years across the world
across the board uh BPA not sure what
that is phalates hormone hormone
endocrine disruptors you use plastic
everywhere you have substances that
leech out of from the plastic and and
mess up people's hormones uh you have
all these issues and it's it's like it's
like the perfect storm everything comes
together to create this this ma major uh
disruption. No. So does it mean that
there allegedly could be a move from
major corporations who are all
coordinating in order to create this
perfect storm or is it just the outcome
of you know several decades maybe seven
eight decades of the way we have been
doing things right dumping stuff into
the oceans and whatn not you know as if
there's no tomorrow and eventually
tomorrow catches up with you. I'm not
sure if there's a conspiracy, but
whether there's a conspiracy or not
doesn't matter because here we are right
now. We the oceans are full of plastic.
Uh there's over fishing happening. If
this continues, you could have anoxic
oceans
that could lead to a mass extinction
event possibly. You know, we we've had
mass extinction events in the past that
were precipitated by anoxia in the
oceans. So, what's anoxia? Depletion of
oxygen levels in the oceans. What causes
that? Multiple factors. But yeah, you
know, choking the oceans with plastic
which kills off marine life in
combination with over fishing which
depletes you know fish stocks that can
cause you know imbalances in in the
ocean ecosystems and a mass extinction
could start from the ocean. You know the
oceans dying out and uh no longer
producing the the amount of oxygen that
we need. um you know we to understand
much of the oxygen we breathe come come
comes from it's produced by phytolanton
that that's microscopic organisms that
live in the ocean and you mess up the
oceans you're going to affect that so
I'm not sure if it's a conspiracy I'm
not sure if there are governments that
have decided that their corporations are
going to do all this stuff and poison
the world and have declining population
levels and all I'm not sure if that's
the case
I'm not saying it's it's out of the
question. It's definitely not out of the
question, but I don't know if that is
the case, right? Uh but whether it's a
conspiracy or not, this we know exactly
what's happening. Um you know, if you
look at the surface biomass,
the the biomass of the planet
today, it's it's mostly human beings and
domesticated animals, maybe 1% or 2%
wild animals. Now 60 50 years ago it was
like 80% 90% wild animals. So see what
we've done. Um and it's not we who did
this. It's the powerful nations that
have done this. Much of this has
happened in Africa. Deforestation and
and just the culling of millions and
millions of animals vast herds of
elephants animals. Where's where are the
elephants? Where are the wild wild
beast? Where are the zebras? all these
animals that that used to tee across the
African landscape. There's hardly
anything left now. The Europeans have
shot everything to death.
So yeah, that's where we are and that's
that's you know, we could be facing a
major crisis if if not us, our
descendants one generation down the
line. Um yeah, it's it's a pretty bleak
situation right now actually.
Okay. thoughts on Zaros, a Brahmin naked
philosopher who traveled to Athens in 19
BC and famously emulated himself alive
in the presence of the Roman Emperor.
Thoughts? Um, I don't know what thoughts
to give about that. It's something that
that happened 2,000 over 2,000 years ago
and uh the the Greeks recorded that,
didn't they? Didn't they? So why would I
mean obviously his name would not be
Zaros. Zaros is the Greek version of
what whatever his actual name was. He
was uh a Brahman, right? Naked
philosopher or whatever. Um and for
whatever reason, he decided to end his
life on the funeral p and in the
presence of the Roman emperor. Why would
he do such a thing? I have absolutely no
idea. Uh the Greeks record that maybe he
wanted to impress the Roman emperor or
whatever. I'm not sure what would cause
someone to do that. So I'm I don't
really have too much of thoughts about
this. It's an interesting it's an
interesting historical occurrence. It's
an interesting historical record. See
a lot of a lot of times there is this
allegation that's thrown out at Indians
at India at Indian culture civilization
that we had this practice of forcing
women to burn themselves alive after
their husbands died. The fact is that
this was a very very fringe occurrence.
happened very rarely and women who
decided to do this were very strongly
discouraged and dissuaded from doing so.
Their family members would come their
siblings, their parents, their children,
they would plead not with the woman not
to do that. So it happened in the rarest
of rare circumstances and then there was
this atrocity literature that the
British created in order to precipitate
you know to justify Christian
conversions that Hinduism is evil and so
on. But th this example Zarmos for
example, it shows that it was it's it's
not like it was only women who did that.
Even men did that. I mean you have
multiple examples from history
especially in Dharmic culture where we
have examples of men who emulated
themselves alive. There is this very
famous uh Vietnamese monk uh Vietnamese
monk self emmonation right uh in the
1960s.
Yeah Kuang Duk. So
okay you know trigger warning because
these days we don't do that trigger
warning. Uh don't watch don't watch it
if you have a weak constitution weak
heart. But this this thing happened
right this this monk he emulated himself
alive to protest the Christianization of
his country of his of his culture. He
was a Buddhist monk a dharmic monk
right? So this is something that's been
part of dharmic culture. This is this
has been done in the past as as you know
if you if somebody wanted to repent of
of a sin or something they did they did
wrong or to re reto their honor very
similar to the Japanese practice of
sepoku or harakiri and also in you know
as in protest you would do that in
protest as well there was this there's
this famous example of a king in Gujarat
whose sons disobeyed him and and and and
retrieved gold treasure etc from a ship
that had ship that had been shipwrecked
near the Somnath temple and the king
forbade his sons from going and taking
that treasure but they went and did that
anyway so the king said I have been
shamed my family has been shamed so he
goes to the center of the city puts up a
funeral p and emolates himself right so
you've had these examples in in Indian
history in in the history of uh dharmic
cultures many such examples
Krishnant Boraloy says we put 30%
tariffs on US pulse imports. What are my
thoughts? All right, give and take, push
and pull.
All right, so India is demonstrating to
the US that you know what uh we are not
going to be pushovers. You're going to
impose tariffs on us. We're going to
impose tariffs back on you and let's see
how uh this game goes. So clearly a well
thought out strategy and we'll wait and
watch and see how it goes.
Prrenav Nile says, "Why did the white
colonizers engage in the Atlantic slave
trade and not use Native Americans as
slaves instead of genociding them?"
Well, you see, there are multiple
reasons for that. First of all, maybe
the Europeans thought that Africans made
better slaves. They were more dosile or
whatever, right? not my words, probably
their words that maybe Africans were
better suited for hard labor and they
were more obedient and so on. Perhaps
that's one of the factors. Secondly, the
natives, native Americans, they were
very
used to the climate, to the weather.
They they did not need so much help and
shelter and whatnot from the from the
from the from the enslavers. So if you
were a black slave, you had no
understanding of the climate, the
geography, whatever. Right? And to stay
alive, you would completely you would be
completely helpless. And to stay alive,
you would completely depend totally you
depend totally on the on the on the
white master, right? Who would give you
warm clothes or whatever. And you would
not know how to survive if you escaped.
So that's why black p, you know, black
slaves would probably never attempt to
escape. The Native Americans, they knew
how to survive the climate. They knew
the geography. They knew exactly where
to escape. Um, they knew the other, you
know, Native American tribes, clans,
whatever. They knew how to communicate
with them. Many Native American tribes
had different languages, but they still
understood each other's culture and they
probably knew how to communicate with
each other. So, if they escaped, they
could make good of the their escape,
right? they could escape successfully
and they would not just die out
somewhere because the climate was too
harsh or whatever. They could live off
the land. They knew where to seek help.
They knew where the other tribes were.
Many factors like this. So that's why
the the the white and so that's why the
white colonizers preferred to have black
slaves. It's not like they did not have
any Native American slaves. They did,
but not as many as the black slaves. And
uh the native Americans were very
enterprising and so on. They could live
the land. They could live off the bison
and so on. And that's why the the
colonizers the the occupiers of North
America, they genocided Native Americans
but also the bison in order to destroy
the u native way of life. Right? So that
is what exactly happened right. Shabish
says Qatar a US partner yet enables
Hamas and Houthis covertly/directly.
Hard to think Israel is oblivious to
this USB fueling conflicts either ways.
What do you think?
We know that Qatar is a crusted US
partner.
When the Americans were considering
handing over Afghanistan to the Taliban,
they engaged in the DHA dialogue with
the Taliban. Right?
DHA is the capital of Qatar. And
eventually this led to the DHA accord
with with the Taliban and some closes of
the DHA accord have been kept secret.
So who facilitated facilitated all of
this? It is Qatar that facilitated this.
Um we know very well that several top
ranking Hamas leaders have lived in DHA
or possibly even now live in DHA, right?
Um, so Qatar is plays a very specific
role in service of the United States,
right? Um,
so it's not like the US doesn't know
this. The US knows exactly what's
happening. Maybe the US is perhaps
possibly potentially behind this. When
you are a superpower, you have your
fingers in every pie. You have a
presence in every geography. You
sometimes want to keep a certain balance
in a certain region. So let's say West
Asia, the US,
you know that you know what, West Asia
has been permanently in crisis for
decades. All the way from the 1940s
onwards, it's been permanently in
crisis. Why is West Asia permanently in
crisis? Maybe it is being kept
permanently in crisis. To maintain a
certain kind of balance of power,
geopolitical balance of power, you have
Israel on one side, then you have
certain nations that are opposed to
Israel on the other side. Then you have
certain US assets that kind of remain
neutral. Saudi Arabia doesn't oppose
Israel. The UAE doesn't oppose Israel.
You have other nations that oppose
Israel and those nations maybe they are
not that potent or relevant anymore.
Saddam Hussein was opposed to Israel.
Right? Where is Saddam Hussein today?
Where is Iraq? Iraq is no longer a
factor geopolitical factor. It's a vasal
of the US. It's it's a colony of the US.
Similarly, Syria now is a colony of the
US. It is currently ruled by in by a
former al-Qaeda terrorist, former ISIS
terrorist who now reports essentially to
the US. So the US maintains a certain
balance of power in the region. It has
nothing to do with what's right or
what's wrong. Power is amoral.
Geopolitics is amoral. There's no right
or wrong in it. It's just about who wins
and who controls the region. And you
will do it in whatever way is required.
Yeah. So sometimes you have to consort
with the nastiest of people like ISIS,
terrorists and whatn not. Well, it is
what it is.
So that's the situation in West Asia.
Sometimes you have to play a double
game. Sometimes you have to fuel
conflicts both ways, right? General
Subatai is a new member is a new member.
Well, General Subatai, always good to
see you, sir. You are one of the
all-time greats. Thank you so much for
becoming a member. I really appreciate
it. Welcome to the channel.
Pranov Nay says, "How did the US and
Canada end up as two separate nations
despite sharing so much similarity?
Also, why is cricket not popular in
Canada although it's part of the British
Commonwealth?" So, how did the US and
Canada end up as two separate nations?
How did uh Mexico also,
you know, remained separate? Um
see the US became a nation in 1776
when uh the rebels who were fighting
against the British government against
the British crown were able to British
the were able to defeat uh Lord
Cornwallis
right Lord Cornwallis was the
commanderin-chief of the British forces
that sought to u that sought to maintain
uh British rule over the Americas and
Lord Cordwallis was defeated
by uh by George Washington and so on. So
that's how the United States became an
independent nation and initially it was
just the the east coast, right? If you
look at the map of the US over the
years, let's let's do that. Okay. uh map
of US since
uh 1776.
Map of US from 1776. Let's see. So what
did the US look like in 17 in 1776?
Let's see.
So
you see um
the US in 1776 was kind of like this
small little place, right? And in the
north you had the French and the British
who still uh very much ruled. So what is
now Canada was very much under under
British rule even after the US became um
you know an independent nation
initially. See the green part that you
see over here that was the United States
that is 1783 and then you have slow
westward expansion. Then in 1803 you
have the Louisiana purchase, you know,
this yellow part that become that that
becomes part of the US. The US almost
doubles in size and then they keep on
going westwards westwards and displacing
and massacring the natives and that's
what happened. But they never bothered
to go northwards because it was
frighteningly cold and not that
desirable. So they allowed the British
to keep possession of that, the British
and the French. So eventually you have
this new nation that becomes Canada.
Part of it is Quebec which is French
speaking. The rest of it is British
speaking or English speakaking. So
that's kind of how it went. The uh the
United States ended up occupying the the
prime territory in North America, the
nicest territory, the most fertile and
useful territory north of the US. As
soon as Canada starts, you get
frighteningly cold climate weather and
so on. Much of Canada is empty land.
only native people are made to survive
there. White people don't stay there,
right? Cuz it's too cold, too
inhospitable
and those those territories are are
given to the natives. You guys stay
there. You guys live there. That sort of
thing. So, um that's kind of how it
went. Now, why is cricket not popular in
Canada even though it's part of the
British Commonwealth? I am not really
sure. I have not looked into the history
of why cricket was not popular there.
you have
um a cricket and curling or skating or
something club in Toronto, right? Where
you had a bunch of cricket matches or
series between India and Pakistan that
were played there. Pretty swing friendly
wickets over there. S of Gang took five
wickets on at least one occasion over
there. Dibbly doubly medium paced guy.
My grandma could bowl faster than him
but [laughter]
my [clears throat] grandma could bowl
faster than Sor Ganguli essentially. But
yeah, he he took five wickets at least
one point. So it's it's a pretty swing
and seam friendly place. I think it's
called the Toronto um Toronto Cricket
Club or something. Toronto
uh cricket
and skating curling or something club.
Toronto cricket club. What's it look
like? It's got a stadium and uh sometime
in the 1990s there was a match between I
don't know
Pakistan was involved and Inam Mulhak
someone was calling him Aloo Aloo from
the from the stands with a megaphone. So
Inam lost it and tried to attack the guy
with a bat and he should have been
arrested for that but well got lucky.
Nothing nothing happened. He wasn't
arrested. So you had so I suppose you do
have some cricket that's played in
Canada but overall it's the US that's a
much more powerful cricketing nation
than Canada in North America. The US uh
recently participated in in the T T20
cricket world cup and they defeated
Pakistan [laughter]
and the US cricket team is mainly Indian
origin players right but that's okay so
there's a lot of cricket that's played
in the US mainly by people from the
subcontinent maybe mainly Indians
we know Ringaraj says I'm a doctor and a
bookworm thank you for opening my mind
to new horizons watch history and
geopolitics learned a lot from you.
Thank you so much, sir. Thank you so
much for your very kind message. And uh
yeah, I do my best. Uh if if more people
get to learn something new from me, even
if it's like a little bit, then yeah,
that then what else can I ask for that
that that that's exactly what I'm trying
to achieve to maybe, you know, spread a
little bit of knowledge that that you
may not have come across before. Uh so
yeah, I'm I'm very pleased. I'm very
happy to hear from you Dr. Vinoding Raj.
Thank you so much for very very kind
message and all the best. Keep learning,
keep growing, sir. All right.
Ironfist OS says, "What language did the
colonizers use when they first made
contact with the local populations of
North America and India?" See, when
there's first contact, the first time
ever there is contact, there's going to
be complete communication breakdown.
you're going to communicate in sign
language and what not. Okay? Because
when when when
the Mayflower Okay, let's talk about the
second attempt to colonize the Americas.
Not not Jamestown.
Americans find Jamestown very
very uncomfortable. The story of
Jamestown makes Americans very
uncomfortable, right? Captain John
Smith,
Mata Oka, Pocahontas, and so on.
Um, that's a
That's a nasty nasty piece of business.
Jamestown, what happened there?
Cannibalism and whatnot. So, we'll we'll
not talk about Jamestown. We'll talk
about Plymouth. The Mayflower comes in
and docks, you know, at Plymouth.
There's the rock, the Plymouth Rock and
and then they find Massasoid and so on,
right?
Yeah. What was the name? Massasoid was
one of them. The Massoid was down south.
Okay. I Yeah, I have to refresh my
memory about that.
uh
but they come across the natives and
initially the the English speak English
right they were Protestants the same as
the French hugenauts and and they speak
English they don't know anything about
the people of the land they just you
know put foot on set foot on and the
natives well at that point in time they
would not really have known English
apart from
one guy one fellow who did speak English
but he came comes into the picture later
so so the point is look there's a long
story behind it you can watch my
understanding America series for that u
but the the point is when two cultures
or two population groups who have never
come across each other first make
contact they initially will use sign
language and some sort of miming and all
that to communicate food water that sort
of thing everyone understands right so
you kind of establish some baseline
communication and then You see what kind
of sound they make when we talk about
when they talk about food or water. I
say water. What do you say? Oh, that's
your word for water. Oh, yeah. That's
your word for water. I call it water.
So, in so after a few hours, you kind of
have a very rudimentary understanding of
what are the basic words, the major
words and over a couple of weeks you
probably can start communicating in each
other's languages at least at a very
rudimentary level. So, that's how it
goes and that would have happened in
India as well. when the first when the
Portuguese first came obviously see the
Portuguese Vasco the Gama he when he
came to India he came to India under the
guidance of uh an Indian sailor right
when Vasco Dama reached the Cape of Good
Hopeed
the Cape of Cape of Good Hope and when
he was in East Africa he thought that he
had the best ships in the world and then
he saw this gigantic Indian ships that
are like three four times larger than
his ships and he saw Indians have been
here for a very long time so clearly he
know that he knew that now I can reach
India because this is a place where
Indians have a significant presence. So
then he took help took the help of one
Indian sailor. Some say he was a
Gujarati sailor or whatever and that's
how he he was able to reach uh Kalikut
Calikut probably right Koli
uh and during the journey if the
Gujarati guy or the Indian guy was with
him I suppose he and his crew would have
learned something about Indian languages
from him right so that would have given
them some kind of you know background in
Indian language and communication and so
on so yeah that that's how it how it
would have gone
Pranov says, "What's the foundation of
the strong USI is relationship? What
drives their partnership beyond shared
values and strategic interests?" Could
you dive deep into this and give a
detailed breakdown?
So
you see there are two kinds of
relationships.
A relationship of shared values and a
relationship of shared interests. When
the US talks to India, they say we have
shared values, democracy and blah blah
blah blah blah blah. Values, values,
this intangible mystical substance
called values. So when they talk with
India, the Americans they talk about
shared values. When they talk to
Pakistan, the Americans talk about
shared interests because interests over
supersede values. Interests always
supersede values. If uh I I have certain
values but I'm shown a pot of gold, my
values may disappear potentially. That's
human nature, right? So interests always
supersede values. When it comes to the
US and Pakistan, it's always shared
interests. When it's US and India, it's
shared values. Maybe with the US and
Israel, it is shared interests plus
values possibly, right? Uh what's the
interests? Well, Israel, what is Israel?
Is Israel's interests? it is to remain
in existence and be the most powerful
nation in West Asia which it is. So that
is Israel's interest. It knows that
there are many nations in the region
that are hostile to its existence that
seek to seek to erase it from the map of
the world. For example, Iran
since 1979, we have the regime of the
ayat laws in Iran and they regard the US
as shayan shaitan borg the great Satan
and they regard Israel as number two
shaitan right and they say that Israel
has no right to exist. So you have such
existential threats in the region when
you are Israel. So Israel seeks to
continue existing and to continue
existing it needs to be the most
powerful nation in the region. it needs
to have a nuclear deterrent which it
does have. So that's Israel's uh
interests in in in in a nutshell. What
is the US and its interests over what
are the American interests in the
region? Well, energy energy it's it's an
energy richch region oil gas and the US
seeks to have complete control over the
nations in the region. Well, most of the
nations are US allies, assets, vasals,
whatever you want to call it, same
thing, right? And they play and they
pay, you know, regular tribute to the US
by buying tremendous quantities of very
expensive American weapons. And they
allow the US to control to dictate where
you can sell oil, where you can't sell
oil. The Saudis have been a little
naughty recently because they've been
selling oil to China in yuan, which is
very naughty, and the US obviously will
have taken note of that. M yeah so
despite that Saudi Arabia has mainly a
US asset a US you know ally it very
recently bought a tremendous quantity of
American weapons ammunition right
tremendous quantity tremendous quantity
of beautiful American weapons that sort
of thing um
so that's the US
um set of interests in the region to
control the nations to offset threat
threats like Israel, like Iran, right,
by by arming and by arming all its all
its allied nations in the region and to
to keep Israel the most powerful nation
in the region so that even the American
allies will stay in check. So the US
seeks to create to to have a specific
very clear very specific balance of
power in the region and Israel is vital
for that. So that you can see that there
is a significant shared interests
between the US and Israel visav West
Asia. And of course you see Israel is an
is a Jewish nation. You have a
tremendous Jewish diaspora in the US.
There was a time in the 1930s when New
York was more than 30% Jewish. You still
have very very uh significant Jewish
population in New York. Uh the Jewish
people are very enterprising. They are
very brilliant and they rise to high
positions in whatever uh country they
live in. uh so you have many Jewish
people who are in high positions in the
you know in US politics in US government
and all and because of that influence
also you have you know a very very warm
outlook towards Israel from the US and
so on. So that's the kind of you know f
those are the factors that are the
foundation of the very strong very
robust long-lasting USIsrael
relationship. It's beyond shared values.
It's beyond strategic interests. It's a
very long-lasting long-term
relationship. All right.
Okay. Next question is not a question.
Swap
swapnant. Swapnant. Thank you very much.
Swapand G. Thank you.
Om Popali says, "Why is Afghanistan much
more Islamized than any Muslim nation
even the even Iran? They are super super
Islamic it seems. What are my thoughts?"
Okay.
Um Afghanistan is way more Islamized
than for example even Iran
because
you to look at the history see
Afghanistan was ruled by various kings
like what are the names
the so the the the the guy who turned
Nuristan into Kafiran sorry Kafiran into
Nuristan uh what was his name Abdul
Rashid or whatever
Kafiristan
Nuristan. So who did this? Okay. Okay.
Amir Abdul Rahman Khan. So Nuristan was
this place where you had Hinduism in
Afghanistan. Okay. See Google will say
it's people practiced ancient
polytheistic religions. I mean what are
the polytheistic regions of south of of
the the subcontinent? It's obviously
Hinduism. So the people practice
Hinduism and then Abdul Rahman Khan for
possibly converted the people to Islam
and renamed the area Nuristan. So
Afghanistan
why is it so Islamized is the question
once again coming back to it. Look
Afghanistan is the first part of India
that was Islamized. It is the original
Kashmir.
It is the first part of India. It was it
used to be called Gandhar historically
for thousands of years. And the Turks
were able to first succeed in conquering
which part of India? Gandhar. And they
were able to first Islamize that part of
the of India. At that time about a
thousand years before today the
population of Gandhar was primarily
Buddhist and whenever you've seen this
across central Asia etc. Wherever you
have Buddhist populations the conversion
to Islam is very rapid. Wherever you
have Hindu populations it's it's very
tough to convert them to to Islam. So
Central Asia became Islamic so rapidly
because it was mainly you know Buddhist
territory.
Same about Gandhar. A thousand years
ago, it was mainly a Buddhist population
and the Buddhists all converted to Islam
and until the 21st century, you still
had Hindus and Sikhs there, but no
Buddhists.
Um
so um a thousand years ago Afghanistan
was converted to Islam. The majority
population became Islamic Muslim. The
Hindus remained in existence until the
20th 21st centuries. Right? And within
Hindus we also include the Sikh people,
right? Um so so it's it's got a thousand
year history of Islam. And then what
happened is that the Turks who ruled
Afghanistan. So the first Islamic rulers
of Afghanistan were the Guris. The Guris
were originally Buddhists and they
converted and they the population
converted and then you had Gazni Mahmud
of Gazni, right? He was a Turk. So then
Afghanistan is ruled by the Turks for
centuries centuries centuries.
and they bring in other population
groups from central Asia. They bring in
the Turkmans, they bring in the the
Hazaras came, it's a different story.
We'll not go there. The Usuzbcks
uh and so on. So multiple Turk ethnic
groups become part of the Afghanistan of
the Afghan population. The core people
obviously are the Pashons
who were originally Hindus and Buddhists
mainly Buddhists and before that Hindus.
Um
so it's got the longest oldest Islamic
history in the subcontinent but Iran
became Islamized before Afghanistan
right before Gandhar.
So what what's the deal there is the
question. I think you see the deal is
that uh even even Iran Persia was ruled
by Turks for several centuries. I when
Chingghistan went after Persia which was
the quaras empire he went after the
Turks who were ruling Quorasma but well
the population well it also suffers when
this happens. Uh so the Turks were
ruling Persia and also Afghanistan and
then you have native U kings who also
ruled like the Suris and all right Sher
Shasuri of course he was born in Bihar
and he ruled Delhi but he was Afghan and
then you have the Duranis
who were pashon but who would have Turk
blood and so on. [snorts] So it's it's a
con complicated convoluted history. But
when we come to the 20 20th century so
there's a period of time when
Afghanistan is kind of secular
officially at least at least in the
cities you have you know people wearing
European clothes and all. Uh in the in
the in the rural rural areas people
would still be wearing boras and whatnot
but in Kabul
people would wear western clothes that's
how it was in in the in the middle of
the 20th century. And then you have the
sore revolution. The the the um Soviets
invade and then the Americans aim you
know arm Pakistan. They they they they
tap into the Pakistani madras and
whatnot and um they they they forment
the mujahedin
um actions against the Soviet Union. So
crossber infiltration of mujahedin from
Pakistan into Afghanistan and the
mujahedin are super radicalized people
who come come from Madras and Pakistan
and they overall later over time they
start taking over parts of Afghanistan
and and repelling the Soviets. by 1989
or wherever the Soviets leave and they
leave behind this government of Najibah.
But large parts of Afghanistan come
under the sway of the Mojahedines
[snorts] who are radical Islamists,
right? And eventually by the Najabula
meets a very nasty end. Um and Kabul is
taken over by the by the Mujahidines.
And then you have civil war between the
various Mujahin factions
versus Abdul Rashid Dustam versus
whoever else and so on so forth. Sigbat
Mujadi Bhan Rabani and they are all
fighting each other bang by bang and
they're all Islamists
and under their rule obviously
Afghanistan whether the people of
Afghanistan even if some of them were
secular they have to become full full-on
Islamized where the borcas and whatn not
have beards right uh and then you have
the Taliban route and so on so over time
because of the way things happened and
the kind of people who rule Afghanistan
that's why Afghanistan became way more
Islamized than even Iran today Right.
That's the kind of story it has seen
history. It has seen
a Roman Beij says aroma beu says does
Jews influence the US? Do Jews influence
the US or its economy or deep state
doesn't have any religious ideology? I'm
curious about my thoughts about it. I
think the Jew the Jewish diaspora in the
US is super influential. It is super
influential in um in business. It's
super influential in um in in Silicon
Valley for example whether it's Google
page and brain whether it is uh uh
Microsoft
um Zuckerberg who's also Jewish right um
super influential in in in big tech in
Silicon Valley and obviously you have
plenty of Jewish politicians who have
risen to great prominence. So the Jewish
people are very enterprising. They are
obviously a brilliant people and they
have uh found ways to succeed far in in
regions that are in nations and
countries and kingdoms and empires that
are far from their place of origin. And
so it's clear that the Jewish people are
very influential in the US. They do
influence uh the economy. They do
influence uh US politics. Um I'm not
sure about the deep state. The deep
state, what is the deep state? What's my
definition of deep state? Clearly the
deep US deep state does exist. It is a
small number of people. Maybe it's all
men. Maybe it's 150 men as Chamat Pali
Hapitia would say who rule the world
behind the scenes. Now are Jewish people
part of that? I could not possibly
comment about that because I have no
idea. But clearly from what we see
whether it's the economy, whether it's
big tech, whether it's Silicon Valley,
whether it is US politics, the Jewish
people are indeed very influential and
that's not some some some kind of
secret. It's it's pretty well known to
everybody.
Vive Singh says, "You have advocated
hard power on soft over soft power, but
except for the Navy, most of our defense
PSUs are incompetent. How will they
change? Can the private sector help?"
Well, the private sector can help, but
only if the defense sector wants to be
helped, right? Let's say I am a private
sector manufacturer. I am manufacturing
howitzers.
Well, I'll manufacture the best
howitzers in the world, artillery
pieces. But if the armed forces are not
willing to buy my armed artillery pieces
pieces, what on earth happens, right?
Kalyani, Baba Kalani.
Uh let's see.
Kalyani, Baba Kalyani, the managing
director of Barat Forge. What is Barat
Forge? Okay, Barat Forge is this
outstanding
uh multinational company Indian company
involved in forging, automotives,
energy, construction, mining, railways,
marine, aerospace and defense
industries. They manufacture some of the
best artillery uh equipment in the
world. But does the Indian government
buy it for the armed forces? Not really.
So you see you may have high quality
defense u
you know manufacturing in the private
sector but if the armed forces are not
interested in buying it if the
government doesn't care then what
happens
right hard power is
is is essential hard power is is is uh
indispensable
hard power always trumps soft power
uh But I don't know what the Indian uh
defense uh procurement process is.
I mean
some people would allege that you know
there's an import lobby or whatever. I'm
not sure how true or false it is. I am
not deep into defense analysis and
whatnot. But there are a lot of lots of
people who you know very respectable
repeated reputable commentators who say
that there is this defense lobby that
seeks to to to this this import lobby
that seeks to import all defense
equipment from other countries even
though you may be manufacturing better
equipment of the same type that you're
importing in India. So that's an issue
right? Uh I think the government of
India needs to crack the whip and and
step in but maybe there are entrenched
interests and whatnot. I think it's
super complicated, super convoluted and
maybe the government of India, central
government isn't powerful enough to
defeat these lobbies or whatever. I'm
I'm not sure what the deal is. Yeah,
that's the issue. That's why I keep
advocating reforms. We need to reform
all this stuff and and and align
all of our institutions with the with
the national interest.
Everything you do should be 100% aligned
with the national interest. Let's say
you want 100
how it serves.
So you need them right now which means
you should not take 73 years to do the
procurement procedure and then you want
ideally to buy it from Indian
manufacturers.
So even if the Indian manufacturer it is
you know the quality is maybe 10% less
than the thing you're importing from
outside you should still get it from the
Indian manufacturer because the price
will be cheaper and you can buy more
and overall it'll do it will still work.
So
so the the processes should be aligned
with the national interest the the
policies should be aligned with the
national interest but I'm not sure it's
if that's entirely the case right now
and that's a major issue. So we need
reforms but where are the reforms? Yeah.
Gapati says recent reports have said
have shown that the Balo liberation army
is using starling for communications.
From this can we conclude that the BLA
does not work for India but rather the
US or Israel. Also if US already has
Pakistan under control what use is BLA?
So I have not seen these reports. Okay.
I'm not aware of this. I cannot
corroborate what you're saying. Let let
us try and quickly take a look at this.
Uh, Balo, Liberation Army,
Starlink. Do do we have a connection?
Tactical use. They've used Rumble and so
on. Starlink. Starlink. Do we have
Starlink deals?
Uh, Starlink repeatedly, reportedly. So,
I'm not seeing anything right now over
here.
Do we have Sajjid Aziz? So Jade Aiz Star
link
uh Starlink there's no there's no hit
for Starlink I'm I'm not sure about this
u not sure where you've heard about this
but I am not able to corroborate that in
the in 30 seconds maybe it may take
longer to corroborate what you're saying
but okay so I haven't seen any evidence
of the Balo liberation army using
stalling for communications maybe it's
true maybe it's not whatever it is maybe
it's true because you've seen it okay So
hypothetically if the BLA is indeed
using Starlink
it means that the US has given them
access to Starlink
or maybe they have somehow acquired the
Starlink hardware you know the receiver
or whatever and they are using it.
Uh what does it indicate? It's it
without the specific information
about whether they have been given
Starling access by the US or not or
whether they have simply somehow
acquired you know the hardware and are
using it surreptitiously. Without that
information I can't say who they are
working for. I don't think the BLA works
for India in any official capacity.
India has been talking about Balojasthan
from time to time but have we are we
actually supporting the BLA? the
Pakistanis claim. So, but where's the
evidence? Maybe the BLA are are being
supported by Afghanistan, maybe by Iran.
Who knows? I don't know.
Right? So, I first of all don't know
whether the BLA works has ever worked
for India. They have sought Indian
support. Of course, they will seek
Indian support. India is the mother
nation, right? India is the mother
nation. They will seek support. But has
India ever supported the BLA? I think
2014 2015 whenever Prime Minister Modi
said something about Balachasan from the
red fort after that has something
actually happened I'm not sure. Uh so I
don't know if the BLA ever worked for
India was or or was ever supported by
India. Is there a possibility the BLA
works for the US or Israel? Well, if
they were working for the US or Israel,
they would not be fighting the
Pakistanis, right? They would be
fighting the Iranians. The BLA is not
fighting the Iranians.
So that would strongly indicate the BLA
is not fighting is is not being um used
as an asset by the US or Israel. So
there is a posity of information. Uh
without that information I can't say one
way or I can't say it's this way or that
way one way or the other. I really can't
say you need more information to be able
to make you know a clear uh case for be
doing this or that
died in plane crash says does China even
have the legs to reach the Arctic and
Greenland? Your opinion on India's
recent focus on submarines also tua has
joined had joined the USSR voluntarily
in 1944.
Okay, multiple pieces of thing. Um, tua.
First of all, those of you who are
wondering where is tua? Have we opened
the map today? Have we not? It's been 1
hour. It's been 1 hour 12 minutes. We
should use maps. Yes. So, where is tua?
Where is the tua region of Russia? Tua
Russia.
Tua Russia. Tua Republic. Okay. Is here.
So, it's north of Mongolia, right?
Historically part of Mongolia.
So there's parts of Mongolia that have
been gobbled up by the USSR which are
which are now part of Russia and there
are there's a big chunk of Mongolia
that's been gobbled up by the Chinese
which they call inner Mongolia. The
original Mongolia was much larger than
today's Mongolia. First of all
understand that now Tua Republic became
voluntarily part of USSR 1944. Okay.
Okay. I'm I'm I'm not very clear about
the history of Tua but okay. Now the the
question really that you really asking
is does China even have the legs to
reach the Arctic and Greenland? So the
Chinese have ships they have ships.
There's a specific kind of ship called
the icebreaker. The Chinese have
icebreers. The Chinese are very
ambitious
unlike India. The Chinese are very
ambitious. So they have the technology
to operate in the Arctic or the
Antarctic or in the Greenland region
with all the fjords and whatnot. You
know, if you if you're traveling from,
let's say, London to New York or London
to the US, you're going to fly over
Greenland. And if you're not asleep and
if you look out the window, you're going
to see the the fjords and whatnot of
Greenland. So, if you're doing that, I
would recommend take a look at
Greenland. As long, you know, it's still
Danish territory. Now, the Chinese have
the vessels, the ships, the ice breakers
that, you know, that can operate in the
region, you know, the the Arctic region.
So, China does have the legs. The
Chinese submarines, can they reach
there? Technically, Chinese nuclear
submarines could make foray into the
Arctic region, potentially reach
Greenland, but I'm not sure the sure the
Chinese uh are risking that at this
point in time. But I've never heard of
Chinese submarines in the in the
Atlantic, for example, North Atlantic,
South Atlantic, wherever. I haven't
heard of that. The Chinese are focusing
on the Pacific right now. That's the
region the Chinese want to enter. Right
now they have been constrained by the
three island chains and that's the major
focus right now not the Atlantic. So the
the so I know why you asking this
because Trump President Trump keeps
saying that you know if the US doesn't
take Greenland then the Chinese and
Russians will will take over. Well
that's it's nice to say but the Chinese
really they they technically
hypothetically can indeed reach
Greenland. I mean send a ship to
Greenland or a few ships to Greenland.
The Chinese can't really do a thing
about taking over Greenland. I mean, not
a chance. Not a chance. Uh my opinion on
India's recent focus on submarines. Good
to see. I mean, uh how many more
submarines are we buying or
manufacturing? I'm not sure. Look, a
nation of India size which keeps on
sloganing that the Indian Ocean is is
our strategic backyard. If you keep on
sloganing that the Indian Ocean is a
strategic backyard, you need at least 50
submarines. Where are those? We have how
many operational submarines? 15, 16, 7,
less than 20. How many submarines does
India operate? Let's see. One second.
Not this.
Um, how many submarines does India
currently operate? How many submarines
does does India operate as of today? 17
to 19, right? Not even 20. I mean if
India
takes itself seriously as a as a serious
nation, India should have at least 50
submarines. So I'm not sure what India's
recent focus is. We I've heard of some
German involvement or whatever. Buy
three from France, four from Germany, 12
from god knows what. Make your own
submarines.
The Chinese, that's what they do. The
the that's what you have to do. So
anyway, it seems that we are building
like 50 ships right now, which is
extremely welcome from my perspective,
but we need to focus more on submarines
for sure.
Baser Bandit says NASA data 2019 says
said that the earth is greener than in
the last 5,000 years. We are indeed
killing the planet, but are there not
wasted interests in hyping carbon?
taxing people like in the EU and the
pure carbon is bad debate is not that
big of a deal. Look, yeah, there's this
entire hype about climate change
um
and so much more. There are definitely
major issues. I mean, the amount of
plastic we have dumped into the into the
oceans, it's it's it's a tremendous
issue. I mean, if you are a fish eating
culture, you eating you're consuming
plastic along with the fish. If you eat
a lot of seafood, you're consuming
microplastic with that, that's going to
infiltrate your entire system inside,
right? You're going to have
microplastics in your tissues all over
the place, in your children's tissues.
Um, that's a big issue.
Over fishing is a massive issue. The
Chinese over fishing fleets all over the
place. They go into the Pacific and
whatnot, Atlantic, South American coast,
and they just decimate the fish stocks
over there. The Chinese do that, don't
they? So that's obviously a big issue.
So maybe the planet is greener
potentially than than in the last 5
years. But what are we doing doing with
the oceans? That's a major major
problem. If you fly over India,
if you are somebody who flies once in a
while, aircraft, commercial aircraft,
take off from any major Indian city and
look out, what you see is frightening. I
took multiple flights recently in the
past few weeks out of Delhi, in and out
of Delhi, Delhi, Mumbai, Delhi, Mumbai.
I mean you take off from Delhi the
moment the flight the aircraft takes off
you can't see a thing outside
and it's not it's not fog it's
hydrocarbons
vaporized hydrocarbons smog
in I mean the people who live in that
part of India it's like you're smoking a
cigarette a minute that's how it is
right and when you land in a place like
Mumbai once again you can see the haze
all over the case. So clearly it, you
know, there are issues. The Chinese also
have this issue. They also have a
tremendous amount of pollution. They've
they've somehow freed Beijing from it.
They've freed the major cities from it.
But you go to the interior parts of
China. You go to go to Shenzhen, go to
all those commercial hubs and all
industrial hubs, tremendous pollution,
right? So pollution is a big issue. And
obviously we're putting out carbon into
the atmosphere that is going to
obviously have an effect on climate
change. Climate change has always been
around. It's a natural phenomenon, but
now there's a human factor to it. So
these problems are indeed a thing. We
are indeed harming the planet, damaging
the planet. We're doing a lot. That's
terrible. Maybe the earth is greener
than in the last 5,000 years. Maybe.
Maybe that's possible. But we are doing
a tremendous amount of harm and damage
to the planet. And the damage
accumulates, right?
And it's the the future generations of
humans that are going to pay more of a
price than we are paying. We are we are
stewards. We are custodians of the
planet. It's not like we have to destroy
it and use it up right now in this in
this current lifetime. It's something
that has to be,
you know, a good home for humanity for
centuries, thousands of years.
Um but obviously like you said there are
vested interests who are hyping um you
know carbon like you say carbon tax in
the EU and all the EU has become overly
bureaucratic
you know everything is super
bureaucratic there's too much too much
red tape there's too much procedure
there's all kinds of unnecessary things
like carbon tax and whatnot they're
shutting down nuclear power plants and
starting coal power plants what are they
doing I just don't get
So uh you know there's nuance to this.
There is good, there is bad, there's
truth, there is some propaganda and so
on. There's nuance.
Vive Singh says considering the US has a
heavy influence on the EU. Can they
twist the Rafal deal? Maybe P75i
in any way to motivate India in their
camp. Your your opinions. Uh what is the
this is a submarine thing, right? The
P75i. This a submarine program. P75i
project. What is that?
It's a significant Indian 6 advanced
blah blah blah
and um it's going to involve Mazagon doc
ship builders and u
RFP has been issued with the marine
systems
as a key and mazagon doc as the key
players and so on. Okay. Okay, so this
group is a German company and if this
goes ahead, if the deal is signed, then
we will now have six German uh
submarines or submarines that will have
German design and technology that will
be that will be built in Mazagon docks,
Mumbai.
So Germany, German technology, German
submarine,
right? That's Germany. Germany is a
nation that has been under permanent US
military occupation since 1945. It is
under US military occupation. Germany is
a US vasal. It's US asset. It's
controlled by the US. There's nothing
the Germans do that is that can that
ever goes against US interests.
Then you have France, the Rafal and the
scorpion submarines as well. Now the
scorpions are done. They have been
built. They are out in the oceans in the
ocean. Uh but the Rafal deal, right? The
Rafal deal hasn't been signed again.
Once again, the Rafal deal hasn't been
finalized. The 114 Rafals or whatever,
it's it's still being negotiated. India
will obviously insist that the Rafals be
built in India. Not just assembled in
India, but even the spare parts,
components and so on be built in India
itself. And the significant amount of
Indian indigenous uh components should
be there and I'm not sure about the
source code access or not, but the
mission computer we should be able to
access it and integrate Indian weaponry
with it and so on. So, it's still a work
in progress. But let's say the Rafal
deal is signed and the this encry
submarine deal is signed the T75i thing.
Then you have the situation where India
is acquiring submarines from Germany and
fighter planes from France. Germany is
completely under US control. So the U
the US can obviously you know do
something about that deal. You know, we
have this deal with the Americans for
the supply of F414 General Electric
fighter jet engines and the Americans
have been dragging their feet over that.
We've signed the deal. We've paid the
money, but they're not delivering
delivering the jet engines. So, they can
make the Germans also delay things if
they want the Americans. No question
about it. What about France?
France is a tougher nut to crack for the
US. The Americans don't occupy France
militarily. The US and French
intelligence agencies see each other as
adversaries. Okay. France has a quasi
independent, semi-independent foreign
policy. They have their own nuclear
deterrent. So France is more of an more
of an independent actor than Germany.
Germany zero sovereignty, zero
independence. France maybe for 30 40%
sovereignty in independence, not 100%.
So the French will be harder for the US
to influence. Germany will do whatever
the Americans tell them. So obviously
this is this can be an issue in the
future and India will have to consider
these things. Keep this in mind. What's
the alternative? Make your own
submarines, build your own submarines.
Um or get submarines from Russia for
example or maybe get Sukoys from Russia
instead of the Rafal. So there's plenty
of options and the government is going
to have to take a call on these matters.
Shanker 3487 says Jumnat Jumnat why is
there sudden mushroom glow growth of
influencers on Instagram and YouTube
showing India in bad line in China CCP
and west instigate youth to do like
Nepal and India against government it
seems planned you see when you have
platforms
that are not indigenous
then those platforms can be used against
you. If India had an Indian
uh version of YouTube, an Indian
platform, right, that is that would be
as popular as the American YouTube, then
you would have full control over what
happens on it, right?
and then foreign countries could would
find it much harder to
have such influencers and and paid
spokespeople spokespersons
uh maligning India on the platform. So
if if you have your own platforms, you
can control these things and you can
weed such people out, ban them, block
them, whatever. The Americans do it all
the time, right? So India could do that.
But India doesn't have any of that.
India is not a digitally,
technologically sovereign nation. India
is a geopolitically sovereign nation in
terms of economy and military and
territory and so on so forth. But
digital sovereignty, India doesn't have
it. India is not digitally or
technologically sovereign. India is
digitally and technologically beholden
vasalized by the west. Right?
So you have this complete penetration of
India by the foreign platforms mainly
the American platforms. India has banned
Tik Tok. Okay. But you have all the
American platforms that have penetrated
the length and the breadth of India and
the minds of Indians. So then it's
obviously very possible that you will
have from time to time or depending on
what's going on a certain upsurge
of the so-called influencers who
suddenly become very popular gain
millions of followers and they they they
show India in a certain kind of light
right they'll instigate people to do
maybe Nepal kind of thing or they may
show the Indian government they may
claim that the Indian government is
incompetent and so on so so forth there
are so many such examples we And we we
don't need to take the names. It's
because these are foreign platforms. So
they can be weaponized against India.
Somir Limbu. Well, Somar G, thank you
very much. Thank you, sir.
PP5K1
says, "US puppet regime Iran or current
regime Iran succeeds with nuclear bombs.
Which scenario is more manageable for
India?"
You see a
a US puppet government in Thran is a
nightmare for India because that puppet
government in Thran will be pro
Pakistan.
It's going to give Pakistan the
strategic autonomy the strategic depth
not the strategic autonomy but the
strategic depth that it has always
sought in Afghanistan. Pakistan has
always sought strategic depth in
Afghanistan but the Taliban has not
given them an inch. So that's been a
disappointing disaster for Pakistan. But
if Iran
regime change happens, if there's a pro-
US government, a puppet government in
Thran, then Pakistan gets that strategic
depth that they seek not in Afghanistan
but in the in Iran in the most
unexpected quarters. Um so
what is the be better alternative for
India? A proakistan Iran or an
anti-Pakistan Iran? Clearly an
anti-Pakistan Iran. The current Iranian
government is no friend of Pakistan.
They know that Pakistan is a US asset.
They deeply deeply distrust Pakistan.
They have even launched missile strikes
in Pakistan in the past. So that is
the current Iranian government. That is
a much better scenario for India than a
pro- US vosalized government in Thran.
That will be not good for India.
Brown Leprechaun says, "How could the
painter achieve whatever he could?" The
painter, Shri, not Shri, we don't call
him Shri. Uh the painter as in Adolf
Hitler, right? How could he achieve
whatever he could? Well, he was clearly
a very capable person. He was a very
charismatic person.
He could enthral crowds. He could
convince crowds that he was the right
person for restoring Germany's honor and
pride and and position in the world. And
after he came to power through that
charisma and through the political
means, he actually implemented the
things he had promised. You know, he
shored up Germany's economy. He he
boosted Germany's economy. He brought
about a complete revival, complete
U-turn in Germany economically. He he
made Germany a major industrial power
all over again. He made Germany a
massively powerful military power and
then he went ahead and expanded and you
know expanded outwards and conquered
territory. So he was a very capable man.
I'm not saying he was a great man. He
was super evil. Of course he was a
monster. No question about it Adolf
Hitler. But he was a very capable
monster. He was a very capable evil
person. That's why
Britic power says why is geopolitics so
addictive? Well, I'm not sure. I am not
addicted to geopolitics. I simply
interpret geopolitics for all of you.
And uh is it addictive?
Well, you know, it's generally
entertainment that's addictive. Do you
find geopolitics entertaining? Is that
so? I'm not sure. So, I can't really
answer why you find geopolitics
addictive. Maybe you can answer it but
it's obviously u something that is at
the center of what's happening in the
world. Geopolitics is all about you know
the evolving world order. Who are the
major players? What do they seek and how
are they going about acquiring what they
seek? It's all about what's it's all
about the unfolding of history in real
time in front of our eyes. And it's
obviously what determines the future of
the world. So obviously it's of the
greatest interest and maybe that's why
many people find geopolitics so
interesting today. It's very interesting
that in 2021 you know in 2021 the the
word geopolitics did not exist in the
Indian consciousness. You had these
experts who were well-versed in
international relations and they used to
call themselves strategic affairs
experts and I think the word geopolitics
entered the Indian lexicon in 2021 when
I did this podcast with Ranir Labadia
the first geopolitics podcast and now
geopolitics is all across the board. I I
think I can claim a little bit of credit
for that. And of course now there are 3
million geopolitics experts in India.
You better be careful about that. Okay,
I'll tell you that. [laughter] Okay.
Okay.
V for Valor says, "Tell us about Indian
navies standing in underwater
UVs."
Uh,
UVs is those underwater drones, right?
What's the full form? Let me just double
check that. Uuv UUV
under unmanned underwater vehicle, a
robotic sub submersible that operates
without a human onboard and so on. Yeah.
So, it's an under unmanned underwater
vehicle. Unmanned submersible drone you
could say. That's a UUV. What's the
Indian Navy standing on this? I'm not
sure really.
This is something obviously you will
keep undercover.
you not talk a lot about um what I have
kind of heard that we have decent UV
capabilities and we are working on those
um
but exactly how many UVs we have and
what are their capabilities how deep can
they dive how what is how what is their
endurance and all I am not very clear
about so yeah this is something that I
don't really have a lot of clarity on
what I've heard is what I've heard only
vaguely is that we have good UV
capabilities. How good compared to let's
say China or the US? I am not sure at
all. So can't really answer in great
detail. Baser Bandit says, "Please talk
about who Captain James Smith was and
what happened at Jamestown." Well, look,
I could talk about it here or I could
refer to you you to one of my videos.
So, one second. Let me um
let me uh
show you.
So,
uh, okay, let's let's, uh, open my
channel. Okay, my channel. And, uh, we
go here. This is the live stream tab. We
go to the podcasts tab. And there is
this, uh, podcast called, um,
understanding America.
So, what what are the episodes here? So,
which is the Yeah, this is the one,
right? Episode four. was a con man
America's founding hero John Smith it's
not James Smith it's John Smith John
Smith Jamestown Plymouth understanding
America episode 4 I I will recommend
that instead of me answering this
question in great detail over here watch
that episode it is extremely detailed
and you will get your answer there but
who was John Smith and so on I will well
John Smith was this English man who
traveled to the Americas and he became
eventually the leader leader of the
Jamestown colony and he saved James
Jamestown from disaster and he also
acted as um as a diplomat. He also
engaged in a pretty pretty
harmless you could say gunpowder dipl
gunship diplomacy.
um and he obviously was very influential
um one of the one of the most
influential early Americans. So James
John Smith probably was the first
American right and what happened in
Jamestown is very uncomfortable. The
Americans don't like to cons they don't
want to recognize Jamestown as the first
European colony in the Americas. They
want to give Plymouth that honor. But
John Jamestown was the first European
colony in America and it was a disaster.
You had massacres, you had uh violence,
you you had atrocities, you had
cannibalism, European upon European
cannibalism, whatnot, right? It was
absolute disaster. So yeah, watch the
episode if you want to know the details.
Ain of Kulkarnney says, "Does the deep
state have multiple factions?" I don't
know. The deep state is something we can
only speculate about. I am not aware of
what the deep state is and who are the
members and what factions are there. I
can't say. I can't say, sir. I wish I
could, but I can't. Right? No one knows
what the deep state is, how many people
are part of the deep state, what their
national nationalities are, what their
identities are, and so on. No one knows
this. It's all speculation. But it's if
you were to look at it intelligently
then it makes sense that something like
that does exist. All right. Okay. Uh
Shankara says Jnath Jat. Did I did I not
answer this question? I think I answered
this question just a while ago. So I
think it's a duplicated question for
some reason but I just answered it. So
yeah. All right.
Rahul
AK says on a sliding scale of
Islamization
how would you place the various Islamic
nations include ISIS and India too? I
don't speak about these matters. Yeah,
these are pretty inflammatory etc
matters and pretty controversial matters
and I like to stay out of I am in anyway
you know some of the stuff I say is
pretty controversial. I don't want to be
involved in every potential controversy
in the world. So I'll stay out of this.
I I am anyway not you know wellversed
with Islam. I'm no expert in Islam and I
don't study the extent of Islamization
in various various countries and all. So
yeah probably I'm not the right person
to ask answer this question. I'm sure
there are many other people who are
experts in Islam and Islamic nations and
all. I'm sure they would do a much
better job than me at answering this
question. So all right
says studying for J but can't see the
point of devoting 12 to 14 hours
studying sacrificing sports and
recreational activities and teen years
kind of I I feel you my friend RDRA I
feel you
so you're a teenager
you have to
somebody wants you to become an IIT
engineer or what enter the IIT
whether you're going to study 12 to 14
hours a
slave away, neglecting your health,
neglecting sports, no recreation,
wake up, eat, study, study, study, go
back to sleep, you know, nothing else. I
mean, at the end of the day, what's the
outcome? You perhaps get get admission
into one of the IITs. Then what? You go
and study another four years, 3 years,
four years, whatever it is. Then you get
what B whether BTE, MTech, whatever it
is and then at the end of the day what
what do you get? You get a job
somewhere, right? Maybe a good package
and all and then you work work work. So
it's like it's just work from now
onwards
and that's not how life is supposed to
be, right? Life is supposed to have some
balance. You should have the good with
the bad. I mean sure work is important.
Work is necessary. Everybody has to
work. But there has to be something
beyond work as well. And by the time
you're a teen, this is this is what is
forced upon you. And I I get it. I
totally get it. I completely get it. I
feel you, my friend. So you got to
decide what is best for you, what's best
for your life.
Okay. So let's say you don't want to do
this. Let's say you don't want to get
into the IIT. Then you need to have a
plan B, plan C, plan D. Three other
alternatives for your career which are
going to be good alternatives for you.
And ideally the career you should you
take should be something that excites
you.
So let's say you don't see the point of
doing this then come up with at least
three alternative alternatives for a
career. Let's say no IIIT something else
a plan A plan B plan C and these should
be convincingly good alternatives that
so for example if your parents are
pressurizing you into studying 12 to 14
hours a day for the J then maybe you
could offer these three alternative
paths to your parents and say that you
know what these three are also equally
great maybe better and these excite me
more than the IIT I may study 12 hours a
day but maybe my mind won't be there in
my or my heart won't be there the
studies and even after studying 12 14
hours a day maybe I will not do well
then what happens waste of time so you
know you need to be strategic about this
so RDRA all the best all the best sir do
well
fields strong man says came across a
video on the great lakes today the US
hit the geography geography luck jackpot
in 100 ways didn't they can you throw
some light on it geopolitic advantage of
the great lakes the great lakes yeah
that's the lake Michigan lake hiron lake
superior and so on so forth see the see
the map, right? Um we have Mary Hero who
was watching a while ago. She lives not
far from the Great Lakes,
uh Minneapolis.
So look, these are the Great Lakes here.
Which are the Great Lakes? If you are,
this is Lake Ontario. This is Lake Erie.
This is Lake Hiron, Lake Michigan, Lake
Superior.
Uh that's Hudson Bay. What do we have
here? That's Lake Winnipeg. It's not
part of the Great Lakes as far as I
understand.
Superior, Michigan, Hiron, Erie, and
Ontario.
These are the Great Lakes. These are
massive, massive bodies of water. I
mean, if we were to uh, you know, go
from Chicago all the way to the northern
part of Lake Michigan,
that's about 500 kilometers. And how
wide is this? So if you were to measure
the width over here, it's about 100
kilometers. Some pretty massive lakes
almost like little oceans, you know,
pocket oceans, massive. If you were to
compare it with something like let's say
Lac Limo in Switzerland. So if you look
at Lac Limo, how wide is it at the
widest point? Let's say roughly widest
point. It's just 13 km. It's tiny
compared to the Great Lakes. If you were
to do a straight line from Neo to Montre
it would be about what 50 km tiny tiny
minus compared to the great lakes. So
the great lakes are massive and uh
obviously you could do a lot of I don't
know fishing. I suppose you could do
some fishing there and uh and uh perhaps
the lakes could be rich in resources.
I've heard I've read in the past about
Native Americans who were mining the
Great Lakes region for copper and
whatnot several thousand years ago. So
yeah, there are multiple advantages of
having this this kind of geographical
feature the Great Lakes. One could be
fishing, the other could be perhaps
natural resources and so on. I'm not
sure about geopolitical advantages, but
yeah, it's a it's a fascinating uh
natural feature.
Rahul a says sar subs crossed 950k band
lifted I don't know
let's hope for the best I suppose I mean
the channel has been stuck had been
stuck below 950 it touched 950 during
operation synindur then it rapidly came
down to 948 and then it kept on
fluctuating 940 949 for like months and
months and months now it's crossed 950k
so so clearly that situation where from
Hey, all the way to December, January,
it's less than 950K. Clearly, that's
unnatural, right? Clearly.
I mean, doesn't make sense considering
the past history of the channel. So,
let's see. Whatever. It's not it's it's
not something I worry about. It's not
something I can control. So, I'm I'm I'm
cool with it this way or the other.
Whichever way. No issues.
Okay. Yet user says YT user 786 says 67.
Okay. I think an average Indian high
school kid is smarter than an American
kid but these changes in college
especially research where do you think
lies the issue? Look even I don't know
if who's smarter who's not overall all
human beings have a reasonable amount of
intelligence. Let's assume the Indian
kid and the American kid on average are
the have the same amount of
intelligence. Let's say okay um the
changes in college especially research
where's the issue? The education system
is the issue. The education system in
India is is trash. It is garbage. It is
rotten.
Okay. And look look I can once again
give you a long lecture about the
education system or I can point you in
the right direction which will which
will answer your question. Where is the
issue? Right? Where's the issue? Why do
why do Indians end up the way they do
beereft of the uh skill of critical
thinking? Indians can't think
critically. Indians Indians have all
these problems. Right? So we go to uh my
channel. We go to the live live tab. We
have a live show going on right now. We
go to the oldest live shows ask 123. And
here we have this iss the these episodes
ask 28 education and India's future. Uh
ask 30 once again education system
problem solutions on the way forward and
31. So I would say watch episode 30 in
which I have spoken about the problems
in the education system and what are the
solutions and what's the way forward
because see look everybody complains in
the world about this problem that
problem but my point of view is that if
you complain about problems you should
also give solutions otherwise shut up if
you can't offer solutions then don't
complain about problems so I have
pointed out all the problems and I have
given the solutions to those problems
problems how what kind of reforms need
to be enacted in the Indian education
system that's episode 30 of Askabit also
watch episode 29 28 and 31 if you watch
those three you will know exactly what
the problem is
right I mean the education system is
designed to keep Indians stupid or to
make Indians stupid when you're born as
a kid you are full of curiosity you're
full of
this boundless interest in all the
mysteries of the world. You want to know
everything. And how do you learn things?
You learn by asking questions. But in
the Indian education system, you're not
allowed to ask questions. If you ask
questions, you are blacklisted. You are
a troublemaker. You ask questions. Shut
up. Keep quiet. You're supposed to
answer questions. The teachers are
supposed to ask questions. That's not
how you learn. That's how you become
stupid. The Indian education system is
all is all about obedience. You know
which kind what kind of kid do do Indian
teachers like the best? The obedient
kids. Not the kids who ask questions. If
you're obedient, if you are a sheep,
they like you. If you are if you're not
that, they hate you. Right? Guess what
kind of kid I was. [laughter]
Uh and and so on. So watch those
episodes, you will get your answers,
sir.
Right. Next. Um, Pratib Kumar Roy says,
"I recently came to know about the city
of London inside London." I recently
came to know about the city of London
inside London. Any details? Is it a
country inside a country like the
Vatican? I I don't know about this. I've
heard something about the city of
London. London or whatever it is. I
haven't gone into any of these details.
So, I am not aware of the city of London
inside London. I am sorry. I don't know
about this. Maybe I should do some
research but and find out if it's really
something. Is it just some kind of tall
tale? I don't know at this point. So I
don't have the answer at this point.
Sorry. Richest Pakistani says, "Paijan
oppon.
What's your opinion on NCM 2025 private
bill?" What is that? NCM 2025 private
billion.
Let me see what this is. I'm not aware
of it. NCM
NCM2025
private
bill
NCM 2025 what is this national
commission for men bill private members
bill introduced in the Rajya Sabha by
whoever to establish a statutory body
under the ministry of law and justice to
address issues related to men's right
welfare men's rights welfare
and mental health in India um to create
a dedicated commission like the NCW
to address grievances such as force
harassment cases,
misuse of laws, family disputes,
workplace harassment against men. It's a
private members bill. The bill has
sparked significant national debate. We
need supporters highlighting the need
for genderneutral laws, addressing high
rates of male suicide
and critics will raise concerns about
the potential to weaken existing
protections for women and so on. What's
my opinion? Uh I will have to study this
in detail to actually voice a proper
opinion. But my point is what I what do
I believe in about this matter? Clearly
it looks like men are being victimized
in India. India is following in the
footsteps of the US.
Nari shak I mean no no no issue with
nari shaki everybody should have shaky
nari as well as nar both should have
shaky laws should be genderneutral
okay and there's no need to emphasize
the shy of one gender or another let
everybody have equal rights equal equal
privileges equal duties laws should be
neutral that's what I believe in and
since that's not the case maybe you
should have this ncm private bill I'm
not sure I'll have to look into Right.
Can't say really.
Uh Pratip Kumar Royce's favorite
Shakespeare play.
Um
okay. Favorite Shakespeare's play. That
that brings me to a whole different
world. I read Shakespeare as a kid, you
know, as a teen or something. Probably
one of the dark ones, one of the darker
Shakespeare plays is is obviously um
Duncan. Not Duncan. What's what's it
called?
Um the murder of Duncan by who murders
Duncan? Lady McBth. Magbet, right? Yeah.
The forest comes marching and so on so
forth. Be bloody bold and resolute. The
three witches.
Yeah. I mean, that's a pretty dark one.
Uh McBth, there's The Merchant of
Venice, there's the Midsummer Midsummer
Nights Dream and so on. I don't have any
specific favorite play. Some of these
are pretty nice actually. Really
interesting stories. Midsummer Midsummer
Night's Dream. A Midsummer Night's
Dream. The Merchant of Venice. Romeo and
Juliet. Ah, pretty tragic stuff. Not my
favorite. The Merchant of Venice and
Venice. Again, not one not one of my
favorites. The Dark One. McBth.
Interesting.
Uh Hamlet again kind of dark, you know,
supernatural stuff, ghosts and whatnot.
Skull. Yeah. So there's plenty of
interesting plays for sure, but I don't
have one specific favorite play. I can
think of a bunch of plays that I
enjoyed.
Okay. Pratip Kumar Roy says, "Is Trump
bluffing about Greenland to scare and
force the Europeans to do more in
Ukraine? Europe is already a vas of the
US. This doesn't make sense." No, Trump
is not bluffing about Ukraine, about go
out Greenland. What he's doing is not
with it's not like he has the objective
of scaring the Europeans and forcing
them to do more in Ukra in Ukraine. No,
he wants a big p big big pound of flesh.
We just spoke about uh the merchant of
Venice, right?
The merchant of Venice.
Oello is different. The merchant of
Venice. Shillock, the pound of flesh.
Yeah.
So Trump actually wants Greenland and
he's going to get it. This is not about
scaring them or the Europeans or forcing
them to do something that he wants. This
is about actually acquiring Greenland
and he's going to do it. It's going to
happen. It's already done essentially.
It's a faith complete. The only question
is how does it get done? What are the
terms of the transfer? That's all. How
much does the US pay for this? That's
all.
YT user says, "I see Indians blaming
current Britishers for our misery and
give back the stolen goods. Do you think
it's right to blame the current
generation people for the deeds of their
forefathers? They just born there." You
can't really blame
um blame someone for the sins of their
father or their forefathers. You can't.
Of course, there'll be some in England,
some some British English people who
will say, "Where's James? Where's James,
bro? Hey, James, you there?" [laughter]
There'll be some English people, British
people who will say that who will
glorify what their ancestors did. And
those are the those are the annoying
ones. But to be very fair, you can't
blame today's British citizens for what
their ancestors did to India. You can't
you can't. Those who glorify that, those
who revel in all of that, those are
nasty people and obviously they are
those are annoying, but well, they're
not committing any crimes, are they?
So yeah, I I agree there. I agree with
you. They were just born there and they
did not personally do any of the
atrocities, the genocide, the hundreds
of artificial famines and the plunder of
hund probably a hundred trillion dollar
worth of today's dollars and so on. They
didn't do it. They're simply enjoying
the the proceeds of that the the the
outcome of that. So yeah. Okay. 1999
says last episode democracy fails India.
Then what's the solution?
Democracy is failing India. Of course,
democracy is the biggest bane of India.
What's the solution? What's the opposite
of democracy?
That's the solution. So the opposite of
democracy is dictatorship, right? No. Am
I advocating for dictatorship? Am I
advocating for Joseph Stalin, Maung,
Sudam Hussein? No, I'm not advocating
for that. I'm advocating for the the the
system that has served India so well for
thousands of years. That is
either monarchy or the imperial system.
The question is who becomes the monarch?
Who becomes the emperor? The best should
become the emperor. Right?
So yeah, it's it's very theoretical what
I'm seeing right now. If I were to
actually implement, if if one were to
actually implement an imperial system,
go back to the monarchy system, imperial
system, who do you make the emperor? Who
becomes the emperor? Right? That's a big
question. I don't have an answer to that
right now. But our emperors, our kings,
they served India far better than
today's politicians do. And they were
dictators. They were not elected
democrac democratically. Was Lord
Krishna the king of Duara
elected democratically?
He was a dictator, wasn't he? Who was
king of Dasharat?
Was he elected democratically?
Did he install his son
Barat democratically?
Barat waited for his brother Shridam.
Then Sriram becomes the king of
Hayodhya. Was he democratically elected
the king of Hayodhya? But didn't he
isn't he one of the greatest human
beings who ever lived right so you know
the solution obviously is what has
worked well for India for thousands of
years but how do we transition from this
rotten system to that solution and who
do we make the emperor's own that is a
very complicated issue clearly Ivanch
says
it might sound naive but why can't the
vasals just stop being host to the
American bases it's a good question
that's actually not a naive question
it's Good question. So how can the
Americans even coersse them into being
vasals? Why can't Germany for example
just say get out?
So what you do is when you vasalize a
country
you can vasalize a country in multiple
ways. One of the ways is to simply
occupy it militarily. Look at Japan. In
Japan you have more than 130 permanent
US military bases. Tens of thousands of
American troops. Now, if Japan says get
out,
they'll have guns pointed at their
heads,
right? There there is there are enough
American soldiers in Japan to physically
prevent the Japanese from re revoling.
Japan can't revolt. There's too many
American soldiers and too much American
military equipment in Japan. That's
there's a reason why they are there to
prevent Japan from ever rebelling.
Okay. Now, it's not enough to simply
occupy the country by force like the
Americans do. You have to completely
transform the governance system. See,
when the British occupied India, what
did they do? They didn't simply occupy
India and brutalize Indians. They they
changed everything. They changed the
systems. They destroyed the the the the
the industrial system of India. They
destroyed uh they de-industrialized
India. And then they allowed certain
industries to exist which would be
controlled by the British. By that they
controlled the Indian economy. Then they
destroyed the Indian education system
and imposed a foreign education system
upon India. That started brainwashing
Indians. The current crop of Indians
with this deep inferiority complex are a
consequence of that. Then they changed
the entire judiciary system of India,
the entire governance system of India,
everything they changed. So today
without the British systems, India can't
can't work.
India is still colonized.
Similarly, the Americans have done that
done in Japan and they have penetrated
the Japanese society to such an extent
that they have prevented any real leader
from emerging.
All the leaders who emerge, they are
temporary leaders. How many prime
ministers can you think of from who have
been Japanese prime ministers? You
currently have Madame Matakei, right?
Who's the prime minister? She became the
prime minister a few months ago. Before
that, who was it? I can't remember the
name. I can only think of one proper
prime minister, that is Shinszu AB. And
we know what happened to him.
Germany, you have some guy who's the
chancellor or some lady who's a
chancellor. What do they do? Nothing.
So, you render the country hollow. You
hollow out its leadership. You ensure no
real leaders leaders emerge and you prop
up false leaders. So by doing all these
things you prevent a nation from ever
rising
and you make that nation completely
dependent on you. All these false
leaders you prop up you make them
beholden to you in 75 different ways
right in such a and the object the
objective is that you ensure they will
never stand against you.
So that's how we do it. That's how you
properly vaselize a country. the and
then then then the Germans for example
had this concept of the uber mench the
master race the German people are the
superior race right the arian race the
the term they stole from us so if the
Germans had this concept of the Germans
being the superior race let us dilute
the race bring in millions of Turks and
and and and people from certain
countries who are from a different race
have them race mixed let's say that's
that's a term some people
and then dilute the race. The race no
longer exists. So then the Germans no
longer have the incentive to claim that
we are a supreme superior race or
whatever.
So that way Germany can never rise again
the way it did in the 1940s 1930s.
Right? So that's how we do it.
Amisha says uh a thousand years of
Somnat's resilience, the eternal story
of India's resilience. Today's divided
Hindu can Hindu society can learn a lot
from sumnat. Well, sumnat is sadly a
cautionary tale for us today. If you go
to snath today, you know viral
sashtra,
you will see a subnath temple there. But
it's not the original temple. It's the
recently rebuilt Snath temple. Nearby
there is this place where you have the
ruins, some of the ruins of the original
Subnath temple.
Right. The one that was I mean there
have been multiple Sumnut temples that
have been destroyed by barbarians. There
was one that was destroyed a thousand
years ago. 1026 AD, right? It's been
thousand years now. Um
and then there was another one that was
destroyed a couple of centuries later.
Then there was one that was destroyed by
Orurange. So every time the barbarians
destroyed it, we rebuilt it. But after
Orurange's destruction of the temple, a
mosque was installed on top of it.
Right? and it was not rebuilt until the
20th century. So for like 200 years
there the temple did not essentially
exist or function.
So yeah a thousand years of Sonat's
resilience kind of mirrors the the ups
and downs India society has has has
faced has had to suffer and the plight
of snad
mirrors the plight over time of India's
civilization. So today you have a SNAT
temple that kind of mirrors the kind of
society we have in India today. The
original Somnat temples, okay, they were
incredibly beautifully carved with human
figures and whatnot. If you see today's
Somnat temple, it's made of sandstone.
There are no carved human figures on it.
It's more plain.
Let's take a look at Snath today, right?
Uh Somnat
temple.
uh if you look at the walls of today's
Sumnath temple
walls
I mean the okay you have some carvings
I suppose but they are nothing compared
to the carvings we used to have in the
past I mean I I have visited the this sa
temple
I'm not sure that I have seen this
mostly if you look at if you look at the
temple you don't see too much
of carvings or whatever. Obviously, it's
a it's a nice piece of architecture and
so on, but it doesn't feel like like the
great temple it used to be. There are
temples in the region. There are older
temples, you know, smaller ones that
feel more holy somehow. So, it will take
time for this temple to to, you know,
you know, evoke that feeling of of being
this great ancient uh site. So what can
our divided society learn from Sumnat?
I'm
yeah I mean learn the history. It's it's
it's a testament to what we have
undergone as as a as a civilization
beaten down so many times and we still
stood up and still standing I suppose
right that's the story it tells us.
Okay. [snorts]
Uh the question is apparently Iran
jammed Starlink. Rumor or true, can't
say for sure, but it looks like there
are reports coming out from Iran that,
you know, Iran has been able to GPS
spoof or whatever and and and make
Starlink essentially very hard to
operate, barely able to connect to
Starlink if you have the hardware
and the speeds are very very low. So,
looks like the Iranians have been able
to successfully at least disrupt
Starlink operations in Iran and make
Starlink very hard to
to operate.
Looks like that, but I can't say for
sure.
Uh, Munabaya says, "Difference between
Indian and Jewish politician mindset in
the US." Um,
Indian origin politicians and Jewish
origin politicians in the US. The Jewish
origin politicians are all united.
Right. And they are all unwavering in
their support for Israel and Israel's
interests. I'm not saying they are anti-
US interests but they also support
Israel. In the case of Indian
politicians, they are the Indian
community is divided in India in the US
and they most of them don't support
India. Yeah. Um
and you know you have this Pila Jayal
who is like kind of anti-India.
Um
you have another guy I'm not sure he's a
politician
Pria
who was behind the Dyani Kobraari
incident right that guy Pri Bara so he
he's definitely very anti-India so there
are many Indian Indian origin
politicians in the in the US who are
pretty much anti-India
and uh yeah so that's a big difference
right clearly
1999 Nupam says India's semiconductor
push and startup space tech India and
global impact
India semiconductor push so we have this
major semiconductor mission that's going
on right now and we are manufacturing
now chips of a certain certain quality
probably it'll take us a decade or
decade and a half to be able to
manufacture the the the highest quality
chips in the world you know cutting edge
chips it um for that we will we will
need our own uh lithography machines
See
you can design chips. Okay.
So when we talk about chips, you know,
CPUs, GPUs, all that. What is it like?
It is a silicon wafer on top of which
you have all these incredibly intricate
and detailed circuits that are etched on
top of them on on top of the silicon
wafer. And so first you have to have a
silicon wafer. That's not very hard to
have. Okay, it's just sand.
Then you have the chip design. That's
another component of the whole process.
Chip design. So much of the chip
designing happens in India. Indians are
some of the best chip designers. Very
complex chips can be designed. So chip
design, you need to have the ability to
design chips. Indians have that. So we
have sand, we have the silicon wafers,
we have the chip design capabilities.
The the third thing is how to take this
chip design that is an abstract thing.
It's a concept and make it a physical
reality on this tiny silicon wafer. For
that you need a certain kind of
technology called photo lithography
machines.
And there's very few nations in the
world that have this technology. One is
the Netherlands
uh they have this company called ASML
that manufactures uh photo lithography
machines. Without these machines you
can't manufacture cutting edge chips.
And then you have China that is trying
to develop the same technology. They
have Chinese origin
engineers who have worked in ASML who
are now trying to replicate the
technology for China. So the Chinese are
super ambitious. What is does India have
for lithography machines? I'm not sure.
So we will need the tech technology if
you want to be a major player in
semiconductors. Let's see. Um, does
India have phototography
machines?
Uh, yes, India does have
photoiththographic capabilities mainly
around older nodes. IIT Mundi, I Bombay
working on advanced photo resistance
systems with new commercial fabs being
built in mature modes. Nodes 28 to 90
nanometers using imported DUV tools
aiming to build capacity and so on. and
so forth so on so forth.
Um
the Indian semiconductor mission
provides support in global players like
ASML are engaging reports ASML. So we
are at we are we need the help of ASML
which obviously doesn't make us an
independent actor in this matter. So
India will have to acquire or develop
photoiththography technology the same at
the same level as ASML if you want to be
a global uh a globally relevant player
in this in the space.
Right now we are essentially taking baby
steps but at least we're doing that. So
good good to see that.
Uh
Anan Rafi Mate says is the AI bubble
real? Look AI is a genuinely
transformative technology. No question
about that. Uh but obviously some of the
AI companies will be overpriced and all
but is this a bubble? Is it going to
burst? Is AI going to end up being a
mirage? not quite
the AI thing, the AI hype is real. Uh AI
is not going to replace all jobs
immediately, but AI is going to
transform the world. Um already it's
transforming the IT sector. I'm not sure
if it has disrupted entire sectors and
and made hundreds maybe thousands or
tens of thousands, millions of jobs
redundant. Hasn't happened yet, but AI
has transformed the way people work and
so on. And uh AI is a gamecher. AI is
being used everywhere as a layer in
various whether it's military
technology, whether it is various
industries and so on. And the
combination of AI and robotics is going
to be a genuine game changer. And the
nation that develops AGI first is going
to have a massive advantage over other
nations. We are probably close to AGI,
artificial general intelligence and
artificial super intelligence will will
be a transformative thing like you know
like a gamecher technology. So the the
AI hype is real and you can already see
how advanced AI has become in just a
couple of years. I mean 2022 23 the
first chat GP versions were very basic,
right? And today they are so much more
advanced. So clearly it's a real thing.
It's not it's not just hype. It's real.
Sergeant Skylon see good to see you.
What is India USA future? India and the
US the relationship is very rocky right
now. The US has never imposed as much
economic
um arm twisting or whatever on India
since 1947 as it has right now. Right?
Very rough period of time. And the US
what does it seek from India? The US
seeks to vasalize India and India seeks
to remain sovereign. So that is going to
be the relationship the next five years.
In the next 5 years if India is not
vasalized then probably India will make
it. India will become a major power but
the chances are higher that in the next
5 years India becomes a US vasal maybe
60 65 70% chances of India becoming a US
vasal in the next 5 years maybe in the
next 2 three years so we'll have to wait
and watch I'm optimistic India doesn't
become a US vasal India does well but
we'll have to see the chances are higher
of India becoming vasal allies because
the US is just too strong and India
hasn't done the reforms India hasn't
developed the capabilities it needs to
become a genuinely independent
a contender for global power. Yeah. What
reforms has India done past 10, 11, 12
years? Nothing major, nothing
transformative. The real thing that
needs to happen. So India is on a let's
say a sticky wicket. Yeah.
So it's advantage US and the probability
is higher that India becomes a next 5
years. Let's wait and watch. Okay. I see
MBS says what's your opinion on our
neutrality geopolitically? We are not
neutral geopolitically. People keep
saying analysts and YouTubers keep
saying that India is India has this
non-aligned
you know stand geopolitically. We are
non-aligned. We are neutral blah blah
blah. That's not the case. We have tried
to be strategically autonomous which
means multi-engagement
not non-engagement not non-alignment but
multi-engagement multi-alignment.
And that's been the policy of India the
past 10 years or so. And I approve of
that. I agree that that is the right
policy for India. We are not neutral. We
haven't been neutral. We haven't stayed
out of things. We have participated in
things. We have kind of been a player
let's say in various geopolitical uh you
know events. I mean we are not exactly
neutral when it comes to Ukraine. We are
engaging with Russia. We are buying
Russian oil. We have been buying Russian
oil since 2022 and we have refused to
condemn the Russian actions and that's
been seen by the US and Western nations
as not neutral at all because it is not
neutral. So we aren't neutral. We have
our own interests and we are pursuing
those interests. In the past we did not.
Now we are. So it's very different.
Godliness says based purely purely based
on science without any religious
traditional or cultural aspect. What
kind of food should an adult especially
men eat and why
you should eat a balanced diet? You
should have adequate fiber
because fiber makes your digestion good
easy. You should have adequate minerals
and vitamins
typically from a plant-based diet. So
you have fiber that comes from plants.
You have vitamins and minerals and all
and phytonutrients
etc. that should come from plants. Then
you need
so that's that's your fiber and
carbohydrates and phytonutrients and
vitamins and minerals and so on that
should primarily come from plants
plant-based food. Then you need to have
fats and protein.
So that generally
comes from animal sources. It could be
vegetarian animal sources like milk and
milk products like you know cheese and
paneer and and and yogurt and whatnot
or animal products like meat right so
you can get fat and protein in copious
quantities from meat. If you want to get
fat and protein from vegetable products
like pulses that comes with a massive
carbohydrate overload
overload.
So you want protein that is the leanest
protein possible without the lowest. See
there's there's something called the
protein to calorie ratio.
How much protein do you get and how many
calories do you have to take for it?
Your protein to calorie ratio has to be
as
as high as possible. High protein low
low calories. So if your the higher your
protein to calorie ratio it is the
cleaner is your source of protein.
So that's what you should aim for and
that typically comes from meat, right?
The protein to calorie ratio for pulses
is pretty low. There are more calories
than protein, you know. Um, so without
forget about religion, philosophy,
culture, etc. Just what's the ideal food
for men, for adult men, you want
what's what is it? What does it say? two
two two grams of protein per pound or
one gram of protein per pound of body
weight which means essentially 2 g of
protein per kilogram of body weight.
Let's say you're 70 kilos. So per day
you should have 140 grams of protein.
[clears throat]
Okay. And your if you are a reasonably
active person your diet should have
daily caloric intake should be about
2500 or 3,000 calories. And if you're a
sedentary person 2,000 calories, right?
Uh so that's the kind of thing and
obviously you should get your vitamins
and minerals and phytonutrients from
vegetable sources. So that is how it
should be
keeping all other cultural traditional
religious aspects aside. And the
cleanest
protein sources are animal sources.
Meat, meat is the cleanest source of of
protein. You can get animal protein from
um from milk products also but that
comes with a lot of fat that is that
increases the caloric load on your body.
So at the end of the day it's up to you.
Obviously religion and culture and all
is obviously a major factor in most
people's lives. So I so it's not like I
am telling you that this is the best way
to be forward.
You need to decide what's best for you.
General Subutai says, "The US leads with
71 nuclear submarines. China has 32 and
China has now officially overtaken
Russia with 28. Where are we? How many
nuclear subs does India have?" Like two
or three.
Uh, okay. Let's see. Okay, let's let's
let's ask our friend Google. Google has
an AI. Um please list the number
number of nuclear
submarines
operated
by US, China,
Russia, India, France, UK. Let's see
what do we get.
What do we get? US 71 roughly, China 32,
Russia 25 to 38, UK 10 to 11, France 9
or 10, India 2. Good God.
So, India is like number six in the
list. We just have two right now.
Anyway, we have two now and we are
building the submarines on our own. So,
at least we are taking the baby steps
and maybe beyond baby steps. The US has
71, China 32, Russia is 25 to 28, UK has
10 or 11, France is 9 or 10, India has
two. So we are in the game now. Yes, we
are in the game. Let's make more, I
suppose. Yep. Okay. Shivan says in a
hypothetical scenario, if you were to
step into Indian politics, which way
would you have chosen? Like a technocrat
or through typical MP MLA system and
why? Technocrats aren't really
politicians. I mean yeah you have some
ministers who are technocrats but they
simply are tools they don't really have
much power of their own. Yeah, you get
elected
and you have power in your constituency,
but your job is that of a techn
technocrat of overseeing a ministry and
uh typically a technical ministry and so
on and that's why you are there and
because you're a technocrat, you
understand the technologies and whatnot.
That's why the prime minister appoints
you as a minister and you do the prime
minister's bidding and you carry out or
whatever is required of you. That's a
technocratic that's the job of a
technocrat
and a technocrat is typically a tool of
a more powerful politician.
If I were to hypothetically step into in
politics, it's not like I have any
intention whatsoever. No intention
whatsoever. Okay, let's be clear about
that. A completely hypothetical scenario
in a parallel universe. I would not go
down the technocratic way. I would uh go
through your not MLA I don't know
definitely not the techn technocratic
way probably MP eventually
emperor [laughter]
because I prefer that system don't I
it's a completely hypothetical scenario
in a parallel universe I have no
intention of ever being anywhere near
politics okay okayir
says could the US be acting aggressive
against India to push it under the
Chinese wing seems seems like all moves
done by all actors fit in this theory.
So the US be is aggressive towards
India. How does the that push India into
the Chinese wing under the Chinese wing?
It essentially if the US is aggressive
against India, it isolates India more
than pushes India under the Chinese wing
because
then India has two options. Either
become American wasal or a Chinese
vasal. The Americans are far far away.
The Chinese are right next door. If you
become a Chinese vasal, they'll take
territory. That is even worse for India,
right? The Chinese are in a position to
exploit India more than the Americans in
some senses, especially territorially,
which is more visible than the real
vasage. Right? So the Americans are not
doing this to push India under the
Chinese wing. The Americans want to
vasalize India. They want to be the
overlord of India. They don't want to
make the Chinese the overlords of India.
They want to be the overlords of India.
That's why the US is being aggressive
towards India. It's it's the US is
trying to cut off India's options. The
US is obviously very capable of doing
that. So right
Gajjapati Dave says your current reading
routine any recent favorite. My current
reading routine I'm not the past few
days I've not been reading a lot at all.
I've been traveling a lot. So it's not
like I have any routine. If I if I'm not
traveling I may read a couple of hours a
day.
Uh, any recent favorite? I'm I'm not
sure what I'm reading right now. I'm
reading multi I'm typically reading two
or three things at the same time. So,
recent favorites. No, I
I'm reading this book by Robert Caro.
Okay. Um, here's a book recommendation
if you want. Uh, Robert
Caro books.
The one I'm reading is this one, The
Power Broker. Very interesting book. So,
yeah, very interesting. Is it one of my
favorites? Well, I'll see if it is after
I finish reading it, but pretty
interesting. So,
okay. Basar Gupta says, Pakistan ISIS
was of US good friend of Israel. And why
did Hamas do a meeting in Pakistan
occupied Kashmir with Pakistan ISIS army
in April 2025? There should be enemies.
There are no enemies. There are assets
and adversaries, right? The US, I mean,
look, they've used al-Qaeda, the US,
haven't they, against Syria in the past.
They've used ISIS.
The US uses all tools on the
geopolitical chessboard.
There is no good friends. There are no
friends in geopolitics. There are no
enemies in geopolitics. There are
temporary allies and temporary
adversaries. And these things keep
changing. All right, please understand
this about geopolitics. There are no
permanent friends. There are no
permanent enemies. There are no friends
or enemies. All relationships are
transient.
Some are more transient and some are
less transient. India, Russia, it's a
more of a stable relationship, long
long-lasting relationship for multiple
reasons. But when it comes to Hamas and
all, the US has used Hamas also. The I
mean Qatar, a US asset, hosts Hamas
leaders, right? Geopolitics is very
complicated. There are no black and
white answers and all that complicated
stuff.
Okay. An anu says, "You have said bat
will keep growing if it doesn't get
bogged down in a war and you have said
Ukraine war has helped grow Russia's
economy. What's the difference?
What's the difference?" That's a good
question. What's the difference? Yeah, I
have said very different things about
bat and about Russia vizavi war, right?
Right. Indeed. See, it's like this.
If Bat gets bogged down in a war let's
say with Pakistan
it means that India if India gets bogged
down in a war with Pakistan that goes on
for months it means that this indicates
India is unable to defeat Pakistan
militarily and achieve whatever military
and political objectives India has which
would indicate this is a scenario where
Pakistan is has been made more powerful
than what it is currently by the
Americans or whoever right so in that
scenario if Pakistan is almost equal
military in in military strength with
India then Pakistan will be able to
inflict significant damage on India
which will
which will disrupt India's economy
India's economy is supposed to keep
growing only if there's no war but if
Pakistan is able to disrupt India's
economy by by damaging economic assets
like for example oil refineries and
whatn not then it is a disaster for
India then India can't road. Do you
understand? If India gets bogged down in
a war with Pakistan, it means Pakistan
will be able to damage India which is
horrible [snorts] for the economy. So
that is what I mean. India should not
get bogged down in a war. You can fight
a war which you can end in like 3 days
or 5 days. That's fine with minimal
damage. For that you have to be
massively more powerful than your
adversaries. That is fine. But don't get
embroiled, bogged down in a war. That is
going to damage your economy. It'll it
may take your GDP growth rate negative,
which is a disaster.
Now, what about Ukraine and Russia?
Has Ukraine been able to damage Russia's
economy? It's been able to do some
strikes here and there, right? It
recently a few months ago did operation
spiderweb uh destroyed a few Russian
strategic bombers and whatnot but
overall Russ Ukraine has been not has
not been able to damage Russia's
infrastructure economy or anything to
any significant extent because Russia is
so vast and Ukraine lacks the power
projection capabilities to damage Russia
and because the war is going on for
longer and wrong longer Russia needs
more and more arms ammunition munitions
for which you need group set up
factories and run the factories which
takes tremendous amount of employment
and generates a lot of revenue for
Russia. So that actually grows the
Russian economy and the longer the war
goes on in Ukraine the more it drains
Europe which doesn't have Russia's
industrial capabilities. So that's why
the Ukraine war has actually made has
made Russia stronger. It has helped grow
Russia's economy. But a war that India
gets bogged down in if that scenario
happens it will be damaging for the
Indian economy. Please think that's how
it works.
Godliness says I know at least five
Indians living here in the west. All are
earning good and also happy but far away
from families. Reason Indian society
relatives made life hell for them for
being gay. Can't we accept them?
Why shouldn't you accept gay people? Gay
people exist, right?
And if they exist, then you should
accept them. I personally would am of
the opinion that people who are gay
should be accepted just like everybody
else. They're not hurting or harming
anybody. What they do is their private
matter. Let them live. Give them the
same dignity as everybody else.
Um I would
I mean I completely oppose, you know,
victimizing people because some because
they're gay or whatever.
I know gay people. They're perfectly
fine, good people. What's wrong with
them? And I'll not take names, but yeah,
I mean, this is wrong.
And and and more importantly, this is
not
Indian culture to victimize somebody for
being gay. We have never done that
historically for thousands of years.
We've never done that. If somebody if
today we have some people in India who
look down upon gay people that is an
unInIndian mindset culturally
it's an Abrahamic mindset it's not an
Indian mindset
Kamat says the US already has bases in
Greenland Denmark is already the Vasal
what's the strategic benefit associated
with gaining direct control is this just
Trump satisfying his ego
Trump wants to be remembered as the
biggest baddest greatest ever president
in US free
the one president who in more than 100
years for the first time expanded
American territory
acquired more territory
and a territory as big as Greenland
almost like the Louisiana purchase
almost like the Alaska purchase huge
territory huge right that's one thing
secondly Greenland lies in a very
strategic location ge geographically
essentially between Russia and North
America and the US is not concerned
about China but more about Russia If the
Russians launch missiles in the US, if
you're in if you're sitting in
Greenland, you will be the first to
notice that. Then Greenland has plenty
of resources that the Americans want,
you know, oil, gas, uh minerals and
whatnot. So, multiple reasons why the
Americans want to have sovereign control
over Greenland, not just have some kind
of agreement with Denmark.
Okay, that's a deal. And they want to
show the world that we are now the
supreme overlord of the world and we
possess the entire Western Hemisphere.
Nobody is allowed to have any kind of
say in that. So multiple reasons for
that.
YT user 7866 says I've read that when
whites left Rhodesia which they say was
the bread basket of Africa the natives
were not able to survive on their own
and this led to hyperinflation in
Zimbabwe. What's my opinion? It's true
but it's not because the black people
are inferior to whites. It's because the
white people left behind a system which
see what the what the white people did
is that [clears throat] when they left
they left behind a situation where the
black people had no skills. They had no
education.
They had never been made part of the
governance system. So they did not know
how to govern a country. They had the
white people left behind a situation
where there was no real leadership. It
was just chaos.
So thugs come to power.
Allegedly Robert Mugawi was a thug and
so on, right? A pretty nasty person. So
they left behind
a sen a situation
where the native people were simply not
equipped
to run a country successfully on their
own. And this obviously led to all kinds
of issues. That's what really happened.
It's not like the whites are superior
and the blacks are inferior. That's why
this happened. That is a very simplistic
way of looking at the world. That's not
the case. Okay. Run
Rajger says, "Do you have control on ads
on your channel?
So many self-proclaimed experts are
selling courses and books even when I
use incognitive new PC." I have
absolutely no control on what ads are
shown by YouTube on the channel. That is
entirely YouTube's prerogative. I have
no control.
Right.
Um
says Nehu versus
Tarbomba who will in
one v one Nehu versus Tar Bomba. So one
is a person Javahal Nehuji the
magnificent. The second is a 50 megat
ton nuclear bomb.
I mean what's the comparison? I'm not
sure what you ask me to compare. You
can't compare a person with the bomb.
You can't.
Rahul says, "Will European tribal wars
resume if NATO does?"
If NATO does If NATO does what?
Uh, look, there's only one thing
preventing the European nations from
going at each other's throats, and
that's the United States. The United
States has kept Europe, Western Europe,
stable and calm and peaceful the past
since 1945.
That's what 80 years now. Yeah. 80
years. The Americans have kept the peace
in West in Western Europe. If the
Americans leave Western Europe and stop
interfering there, stop controlling the
the region, the Europeans will go back
at each other's throats. So the moment
NATO ends and the Americans withdraw
from Europe, the European tribal wars
will resume.
Rishi Barat says posture check and
hydration reminder for everybody. Thank
you for the posture check. Yes, in the
hydration reminder. If the US army is so
powerful, then what are the checks and
balances in place to prevent army chiefs
from from taking over the US
establishment? That's a great question.
One thing you can do
is make sure there are lots of generals
and none of them has too much power and
of course you have the chief of staffs
and all that the the the
guys the super generals who report to
the president. So you essentially ensure
that the army has many generals and none
of them has too much power. Let's find
out how many ar generals does the US
army has have. How many generals
in US army?
How many generals do you have? The US
has a statutory cap of 219 active duty
general officers. One star, two stars,
three star. Um, capped at 219.
So, how many do they have right now?
How many generals are there? So it's not
giving me the exact answer I want. But
let's say you have okay so you have 219
active duty generals and uh more than
250 brigadier generals one star hundreds
more in total across all star levels.
Right? So you what you do is you you
distribute the power you know you you
diffuse out the power diffusion.
Don't allow too much power to be held to
be concentrated in the hands of any one
person.
Right? So yeah, this is a very pertinent
question, very important question. You
want to ensure that no such there's no
such scenario where there could be a
coup in the US, you know. So that's what
you do. You ensure nobody becomes too
powerful. Keep all the generals, you
know, it's if it's fivestar generals,
all the five star generals should have
the equal same amount of power. None of
them should be more powerful than the
other. and you keep an eye on them. If
somebody is showing any signs symptoms
or whatever, then you can retire them or
whatever, that's what you do. If you
just have let's say five generals in an
army, then it becomes very easy for even
three of them to get together and take
over the country. But if you have 219
generals and hundreds more brigadier
generals and whatnot, it's so difficult
for any kind of coup to happen. So yeah,
these are very important things to look
into if you are a major power. ensure
that you know nobody has too much power
in the armed forces.
Godliness says behavior of some
individuals based on their cast
identity, state or religion especially
from North India is very disturbing and
is becoming dangerous and unlawful. Will
we ever have civic sense? I am not sure
what you are specifically referring to.
Um
especially from North India. Well, I
really don't know exactly what you're
talking about. Will we ever have civic
sense?
Civic sense is very easy. Make it you
know make the punishments
certain. If somebody breaks the law or
or or you know goes on the wrong side of
civic sense make it certain they will be
punished and punished heartly.
Enforce that. That will immediately
transform the civic sense of any
country. Go to Singapore today.
Everybody has impeccable civic sense. 50
years ago everybody was spitting on the
streets and peeing on the walls. What
happened? Enforcement harsh enforcement
that is what conditions people into
behaving properly. Pavlovian
conditioning essentially
the Indian government doesn't care about
civic sense. The law and order
authorities don't care about these
things and that's why we have the
situation right. Um and so on and about
this cast thing and all. I have no idea.
Sorry. V4 valor says hydration and
posture reminder. Thank you so much. I
shall hydrate myself once this is over.
Uh okay. Uh but thank you for the
reminder. Indians outsource security
leadership even critical thinking that
became fatal for them. Now you
outsource. You see, look, whatever you
outsource goes beyond your control,
right? It's always a problem. If you
outsource technology,
we don't have any of our platforms, but
we'll use American platforms. That's a
big big um issue when it comes to
technological sovereignty, leadership.
I'm not sure if we outsource leadership.
Critical thinking, Indians are devoid of
critical thinking. Not their fault. It's
the education thing, the system that
does that. But these issues they all add
up together and become massive problems
for a country. Which is why I keep
saying India needs reforms but there is
no urgency or even any scope of reforms
that one sees you know massive major
reforms deep deep rooted reforms in
various sectors in India.
Pratep Kumar Roy says you mentioned the
pound of flesh. Any similarities between
Shillock and Trump in Israel angle
behind Greenland? Um, it's been too long
since I read The Merchant of Venice.
Portia was the the the female
protagonist. Shillock is the the nasty
guy who wants the pound of flesh. I
don't remember what Shillock was all
about. Don't remember the story in great
detail. Similarities between Shillock
and Trump. I'm not sure if I see too
many actually. You know, any Israel
angle behind Greenland? I don't see that
either. I don't see an Israel angle
behind Greenland as far as I can see.
Not really. Okay. Echo 942 says only
education Indian parenting is also
trash. You see my friend, you see Echo,
what did the Indian parents go through?
They went through the same trash
education system. Several generations of
Indians have been put through this
garbage trash rotten education system.
So every generation the effects are
compounding.
Do you understand?
I don't disagree with you. Many Indian
parents are also stupid. They don't know
how to parent the you know be good
parents, effective parents to their
kids. Why is there so many behavior
issues and all people Indians behaving
poorly and all? Because the parents
encourage such behavior in their kids
and that's why the kids are loud and
noisy and they if you're in a flight
they will watch reals you know at full
volume not caring about whether other
people want to sleep or not or whatever.
Parenting is also an issue. But who what
did the parents undergo? They also went
through the same education system. So
every new generation the effects are
compounding. That's the problem. So we
have to reform the education system. But
our fantastic leaders don't seem to
think of it as an issue at all. Maybe
think they think it's a great education
system. Maybe it's giving them the kind
of citizens they want to want to rule
over. I don't know.
Rahul says how good is EU Australia for
masters in computer science AI quantum
plus is legal immigration for education
or work a good idea as we'll be playing
their game by the rules ah look I don't
know which country is good for what what
course I don't look into these things I
don't know when it comes to computer
science artificial intelligence quantum
quantum computing quantum mechanics etc
quantum technology ies right you're
talking about applied stuff not quantum
mechanics but quantum technologies I
would say the number one place for this
would be the United States EU I don't
know France generally has a good
education system but Germany has a good
education system for sure
uh so France and Germany are good but
the US is better obviously
um Australia
I'm
not sure how good Australia is at
cutting edge technologies I don't more.
So all I can tell you is the US is the
best place. In the EU, I think France,
especially Germany will be good.
Australia when it comes to computer
science, AI, quantum, I'm not really
sure. Yeah, I don't look I don't keep
track of this stuff. I it's not it's not
my thing, right? So So yeah, I can't
really answer your question in great
detail because I'm not an expert in this
matter, right? Education,
educational placements and stuff, I have
no idea. uh legal immigration for
education is work is it a good idea will
be playing well look what you have to
ask yourself is where will I get a great
career
yeah where will I be most successful if
it's in a foreign country but go for it
immigrate legally it's it's okay it's
fine obviously you'll have to play by
the rules but it is the it is the name
of the game
u you will not get the same
opportunities in India as you will get
outside India No question about it. And
I highly recommend that if you're a
young person, focus on your own personal
growth and development. The first 20
years at least of your adult life. From
year from ages from your age from the
age of 20 all the way to age to the age
of 40 at least. Focus on yourself. Be
selfish. If you have to go abroad for
that, I would highly encourage you to do
that. Okay. Nirupam says, "What reforms
would be critical to prevent vas?"
Um,
vasalage is something that will happen
or not in the next 3 to 5 years.
It's it's too late for reforms to
prevent vas. But what reforms does India
need is a is a good question. Education
needs to be completely thoroughly
overhauled completely. The entire system
needs to be dumped into the waste
basket. That's how bad the system is.
Right? That needs to be reformed. What
else?
Delete corruption wherever wherever it
it allegedly exists.
Wherever it exists. Then make the
taxation system more rational. Why is it
so cumbersome? Why can't everybody pay
this simple tax?
Right? Everybody is a taxpayer. By the
way, if you buy a buy buy a something
that costs 10 rupees, you're paying tax
on it. You're paying GST and whatnot.
So, it's not like only people who pay
income tax are taxpayers. Everybody pays
tax. Make the taxation system r more
rational. Simplify it. Ease of doing
business is very important.
It's still very difficult to do business
in India. Get something as simple as
getting a GST number is so difficult in
this country.
So the reforms are needed across the
board. Make the bureaucracy effective.
Make the other institutions which I'll
not name effective. Clean them up. You
need reforms across the board.
Reforms everywhere are needed.
Okay.
Manis
Saraswatah.
Thank you very much. Manisatullah. Thank
you so much.
And once again, Mani Saraswatula, thank
you very much indeed.
Mohit Sharma says, "How IKS is different
from modern education system? If all
distortions are rooted in history, then
should we be taught with us and how will
it work?" I am not an expert in IKS,
Indian knowledge systems. I have done a
podcast with uh the director of the uh
Indian Institute of Science Monday IIT
Monday who is an expert in IKS but I am
no expert in the IKS how is it different
from the modern education system I won't
be able to answer you in in you know
effectively or in in great detail
secondly if all distortions are rooted
in history then why then should we be
taught veas and how it how will it work
we should be taught correct history
whether you want to learn the vedas or
not. It's a personal matter. I don't
think the Indian education system
teaches that. I'm not even sure if it
needs to be taught in its entirety.
The Vedas are so massive, right? There
are four Vedas and that's a lot of
reading to do and it's not for
everybody. It's a very high intellectual
level. You can't teach the ordinary per
ordinary person the Vedas. You need to
be intellectually slightly
above average at least to be able to
grasp what the Vedas are about. I would
say
you have to we should teach correct
history.
Forget about teaching the Vedas. Teach
correct history. That's what's needed.
Ujas
UAS
Majit
says really loved your content for for
things since for you. Thank you so much
sir. Thank you. Kindly explain the Bhima
Cora incident 1st January 1818. Did the
Dalith sign of the British? I don't know
anything about this incident. So I'm
very sorry. I don't know about this
incident. I have never read about it. I
don't know who fought whom and I have no
idea. Very sorry but thank you so much.
Thank you. Pratik Kumar Roy says did you
see the film Shindler's List? My
favorite movie of all time. Godfather I
didn't like. I probably have seen
Shindler's list a black and white movie.
Liam Niss and so on. I have probably
seen it. Yeah. Long long long long time
ago. Ben Kingslay and so on. Yeah. Good
movie. Good movie. Not my favorite movie
of all time, but definitely a very good
movie. The Godfather I liked it very
much. I don't know which one you've
watched. I've seen part one, part two,
part three. Part three is not the best.
Part one and part two great. Part two
even better than part one. So, I love
the Godfather series. U but it's it's
okay. We can we don't have to agree on
everything. We can agree to disagree.
Everybody has their own taste and
choices. So yes, I have seen Shindler's
list long long time ago and it's
definitely a great movie.
Aayush Gupta says illegal immigrants of
Bangladesh are mostly because of whom
you think central state vote bank or BSF
who themselves take bribes.
Okay sir, it's a huge issue. It's a huge
issue. massive massive issue and it
needs to be resolved. We can't have a
100 million possibly
possibly 100 million illegal
infiltrators squatting on our territory,
leeching off our resources and taking so
much space. We can't have that. What is
the government doing?
So, it's a huge issue indeed.
Sam the gamer says must meet before
death except me as shisha.
I hope we meet all of you who I interact
with in this virtual form. I hope to
meet all of you someday
before death hopefully. Yeah
[clears throat] indeed indeed.
Pratip Kumar Roy says how has China and
Southeast Asia gone so far ahead of
India and we are left behind. The
difference in infrastructure for example
is huge.
Look their education systems have are so
much better than India. The Chinese have
invested since the 1990s mid 1990s the
Chinese have invested essentially
trillions of dollars into completely
overhauling their education system. They
know that is the root the foundation of
n national success.
They have spent trillions of dollars
reforming their education system. It's
probably the best in the world today.
Then they they they
built highquality infrastructure.
For example, they have a mission the
Chinese that they're going to connect
the entire country through high speed
highsp speeded railways and they don't
allow anything to stop the mission. It
doesn't take 20 years to build one
railway line.
Land acquisition everything is is
streamlined,
right? So they execute fast and they
execute properly. In India, everything
is half-hearted, half hazard sometimes,
right?
And uh these nations have built
world-class manufacturing sectors. What
what do you need to have a world-class
manufacturing sector? You need to have
high quality research and development.
For having world-class R&D, you need to
have corporations and companies that
invest in R&D. You need a government
that invests in R&D. To be able to do
that, you need a high quality education
system. Everything is interconnected.
They they have solved these problems. We
have haven't solved any of these
problems. That's the issue, right? I
mean, we could have solved it. We can
still do it. But is there any political
will for that? That's the question. Do
the politicians even agree that these
are issues? I don't know
with Okay. Do you think the whole UGC
policy release is a sign that leftists/
whoever else are infiltrating the BJP
and will it will lose both UP27 state
and looks about 29 as its GC support
base will move away from it? Look, I
don't listen, I do not comment about
Indian politics, internal matters of
India.
I don't
Okay, so I don't know who is
infiltrating whom and all that. What I
will tell you is that this UGC policy
thing is a disaster. It's horrible.
It's terrible.
It's absolutely against the interest of
the country and and our civilization.
It's terrible. Beyond that, I will I
cannot comment. I will not comment.
Okay. This UGC thing, it it seeks to
divide our our country into two classes.
The oppressors and the oppressed. The
permanently oppressed people and the
permanent oppressors. It's almost like
an apathide policy. It's horrible. What
are they doing? What is the government
trying to achieve? I don't know really
terrible.
Sumit says Trump's Trump invites India
to join Gaza Peace Board FP foreign
foreign policy. Really? Let's see. Okay.
Trump invites India to join join
Gaza
Peace Board. Really?
Board of Peace. But he says that every
every member of the Board of Peace has
to pay a billion dollars, right?
Oh, whatever. Oh, we'll see about it.
We'll see. Okay. [laughter]
Dir Kamad says, "Civic Sense propaganda
has become weaponized by racists and
anti-Indians." Apparently everything
anything done to us is justified because
it is our civic sense. That's also an
issue, right? It's not like Indians have
the worst civic sense in the world.
Civic sense is an issue. You can see the
see the problems.
But that obviously is used in a in a way
that that seeks to demonize India and to
portray Indians as this permanently
backward people and people who don't
belong in the civilized world and so on.
And that will then be the justification
for any any nonsense that's any bad
thing that's done to Indians. all the
Hindu phobia, all the indophobia and
whatn not, all the demonization of
Indians. So that's also a major issue.
No question about that. You're right.
Aish Gupta says how you felt for the
first time when you had a good amount of
knowledge of geopolitics and somehow you
can see your country not doing anything
and every day you have to witness it
burns me inside. It's it's not a good
feeling.
I don't know when I had a good amount of
knowledge of geopolitics
but I it's it's a it's a realization
that slowly dawns upon you over time
when you are a younger person and then
you see it more and more you see the
problems the country is is is beset with
and you see that nothing is being done
about them and maybe some of the
problems are being made worse like what
we are seeing with this UGC thing what
are we doing to ourselves so yeah it's
it's extremely it makes makes you
unhappy. It frustrates you because this
country has the so much potential. India
has so much potential. The people of
India has so much potential. India can
genuinely be the more the greatest
country in the world.
But that depends on the quality of your
leadership if you can really achieve
that. And I'm not saying we have
horrible leadership, but
you know things are not been done
entirely the way they should be.
Uh Brahma Mosqua says, "Are you a
theist, agnostic or atheist? And why?" I
am a hopeful agnostic. Why am I an
agnostic? I have never seen God or gods.
I've never seen or witnessed any
supernatural incident or any I've never
had
probably never had a supernatural
experience barring maybe one or two
things that I can't explain. So that
kind of so so because of that I am
agnostic. I don't know if God or gods
exist or not but I'm hopeful. I'm
hopeful there is God. I'm hopeful the
gods are there and there's one one God,
multiple gods, whatever. I have no idea
but I'm hopeful. Yeah. So that's what
that's my that's my position. I'm a
hopeful agnostic. It'll be so nice if
the gods do exist and they're benevolent
and beneficial and all that. It'll be
great.
Aditya
Varmar says a big fan. Thank you so
much. Thank you indeed. Hypothetically
thinking would applying reservations to
Agnir's government sector jobs and
slightly rolling back cast based
reservations help in inculcating
discipline in our nation's youth
applying reservations to Agnir's
government sector jobs and slightly
rolling back cast based reservations
help in I am not sure exactly what
you're proposing I'm not sure how it is
done in the Agni there is the army thing
applying reservations to GC See, I'm not
sure exactly. It's a I'm a little
confused, but I am not a proponent of
reservations,
castbased reservations.
We need to end castbased reservations.
Reservations are fine. If you want to
give reservations to people, give them
reservations on the basis of their
financial status, economic status.
People who are economically not well
off, store, give them reservations.
Don't give it based on cast man. you're
creating more problems in the country.
That is my simple uh position on this
matter. I am completely against any
castbased reservations. Give
reservations based on e economic status
and that do not forever.
Chaitanya says chavda index 2026 when I
love the 24 version but there was no 25
version as well. Yes, thank you for the
reminder. I shall make a move on that. I
shall move forward with that. Thank you.
Thank you. Uh Pratip Kumar Roy says, "I
found I recently found out that Rig Vic
Indra rides on horses. The white
elephant Aravat was later added in the
piranhas. Why don't we worship the old
Vic gods nowadays?" Because of the
Vishnavas
look thousands of years have passed
since the Vueveda. So much has happened
today. Nobody even worships Lord Indra.
You go to various temples, you will see
sometimes um you know a morti an idol of
dash pitro but you won't find a morti of
Indra in many temples. Why is that?
Right? And okay I'm not aware of whether
the vig indra rode horses makes sense
that he would he would have came later.
You will see statues ofat in in Thailand
in Bangkok and so on and Indra of course
Indrauri is Bangkok. Um so why don't we
worship the old Vic gods nowadays?
Because thousands of years have passed
and so much has changed in Indian
society. Why don't people worship Indra?
Indra was the the greatest of the Vic
gods, right? The head of the pantheon of
the Vic gods. Jupiter, Zeus, Peter,
Zeus, Jupiter, Thor, that's Indra. Those
are later versions of Indra. Same god.
And Indra was the most powerful of the
Vic gods. And Indra was also the god of
thunder, lightning and rain. His weapon,
the Indra's weapon is vajra. Vajra is a
hammer. It's also a thunderbolt, right?
Vajra. It's crafted out of the rib bones
of a great Vic sage. That's the original
original mol.
Now, Indra was also the god of rain,
rainfall. And why did the greatest of
our rivers, the mother of our
civilization, the Saraswati, why did she
disappear?
because of a lack of rainfall. Who was
responsible for that? Indra. Do you
think people would continue worshiping
him after that? After the demise of the
Saraswati, the mother of Indian
civilization, there are reasons for
that. And see, Indian civilization has
existed over geological time scales.
Rivers have come and gone, disappeared
and so on. That's how old our
civilization is. And that's why so many
changes have happened. That's why many
of the older gods are no longer
worshiped. And newer gods have taken
their their place. And those newer gods
are also continuations in some way of
way or other or or other of the older
gods.
Okay. Abi says
masturbation effects on today's youth. I
am I am not your guy. I I don't know
anything about this. I'm sure there are
many podcasters, YouTubers who are into
this uh and who have advanced theories
of these matters.
I am no expert in these matters. Semen
retention and so on so forth. Sorry,
[laughter] I'm not the guy for this. All
right. Okay. Rahul says,
"Is work out and daily sadna part of
your life?" It needs to be more
of an integral part of my life. Right
now, I'm kind of living a slightly
indisciplined life. I've been traveling
a lot the past few days, roughly the
past month and um my schedule is all
over the place. Sometimes I wake up
early, sometimes I wake up late,
sometimes I sleep late and so on. So
right now workout etc is not very much
part of my life. Sadhena
also right now not very much part of my
life. Maybe I should make these not not
maybe but most definitely I need to be
more disciplined going forward. Right.
So yeah,
Abiru Sharkar says, "Twoik men videos
claim women are biologically inclined to
test partners and seek better mates. Is
marriage in India a long-term risk?"
Look, marriage is a is a fundamental
integral societal institution.
It's it's an integral part of Indian
culture, civilization, and society. But
is marriage today a long-term risk?
Well, based on the kind of laws we have
and the lopsided nature of laws and the
lopsided nature of uh the way certain
genders are a certain gender males are
being victimized, maybe marriage is more
of a risk today than it was 50 years
ago, maybe even more than it was 30
years ago.
I I don't know about what Stoic men
videos say that women are biologically
inclined to do this or that. I I have no
I don't know about that. But because of
the kind of laws we have and the kind of
the way the laws are interpreted, I
think u marriage is has kind of become
more of a risk for men. So that
obviously seems to be a ploy to to bring
India's TFR down and so on. That's major
issue. The government should do
something about it if the government
would like to unless the government also
wants our TFR to come down and they want
more disharmony in society.
Okay. Arouch says BTech biomemed student
targeting Deutschand European Unions any
suggestions? I have absolutely no idea
sir. I am not uh in the field of
educational educational placements or
whatever. I have no idea which country
has better options for bio biomedical
sciences and all. I I really don't know.
uh you should consult a professional
somebody who has proper knowledge
professional knowledge of which country
offers what courses and what things and
you should take their suggestions. I
really really don't know so I apologize
but I'm not the right person to answer
your question
and died in a plane crash says one of
the criticisms of Durand according to
people of certain lobby is that it's a
well-made movie and and well-made
propaganda is quite dangerous. What's my
opinion?
Okay, so some people say it's propaganda
and it's wellm made so it's even more
dangerous as propaganda. It's a
well-made movie. It has some small flaws
and defects here and there, but overall
for Bollywood standards, it's an it's
it's an excellent movie.
And is it propaganda?
It's not propaganda. It's truth.
It's absolutely truthful. It's based on
historical events and whatever fictional
stuff is depicted, that's fiction. How
is that propaganda? How is other
Bollywood garbage and trash not
propaganda? How is Joda Akbar not
propaganda?
So don't take these people seriously.
Who cares what the certain lobby says
and what they believe? Who cares?
Disregard them. Ignore them. Why do they
matter? Don't take them seriously.
Durand is fantastic. I loved it. I look
forward to watching the next one. If I
can, I I'll like to watch one more do
one more watching of Durand if I can.
Let's see.
Okay, Dian Crink Crush says, "Does these
ridiculous criticisms indicate their
frustration?" Yes, it does. They are
very frustrated that finally somebody
made a good Bollywood movie that
portrays the truth instead of the
propaganda they've been dishing out. So,
it does indicate their frustration. No
question.
Okay, that brings me to the end of
today's questions. All right, enjoyed
this very much. took a very very very
very large variety and wide variety of
questions. Thank you so much for your
questions. I'm going to end this live
stream here. It's been more than 3
hours. Fantastic. Thank you so much
everybody. Thank you for your questions.
Keep asking questions. Keep learning.
Keep raising your standards. And I shall
see you very soon in next week's live
streams. Until then, take care. Good
day. Good night. Bye-bye. I'll see you
soon.